<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic Report on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/academic-report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic Report on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/academic-report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>An Optimal Pathway To Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</guid>
      <description>In the aftermath of the global financial crisis, intrinsic political and economic challenges have raised questions about the survival of the European Monetary Union (EMU). To the extent that we can view the crisis as an asymmetric employment shock, we are reminded that national level barriers to labour mobility do not make for strong optimal currency area arguments. In addition, price level inflexibility and homogenous borrowing costs across the EMU have resulted in continued high unemployment and disparities in real exchange rates that cannot be met by nominal revaluations (1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Dollar Could Be Good For Canada</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/strong-dollar-could-be-good-for-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/strong-dollar-could-be-good-for-canada/</guid>
      <description>Pundits of the double-dip recession theory cite the now globally anticipated fallout of the U.S. dollar as a key source. The fed is printing money like confetti, they say. The U.S. Treasury bill bubble is soon to pop, they add. The newly coined (U.S. dollar-carry trade) (it used to be the yen-carry trade) is driving commodities through the roof, they squeal. The concerns are many. For example, rampant increases in U.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>