<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Academic Report on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/academic-report/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Academic Report on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/academic-report/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Liberalization And Sector Productivity</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper analyzes the effects of trade liberalization on productivity at the sector level. This is done with a multivariable regression of relative gross labour productivity on sector trade, between the U.S. and Canada, relative to total trade, between Canada and the world. A set of before and after treatment variables are used to distinguish the difference between the effect of trade openness before the NAFTA preferential trade agreement and after the agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Optimal Pathway To Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</guid>
      <description>In the aftermath of the global financial crisis, intrinsic political and economic challenges have raised questions about the survival of the European Monetary Union (EMU). To the extent that we can view the crisis as an asymmetric employment shock, we are reminded that national level barriers to labour mobility do not make for strong optimal currency area arguments. In addition, price level inflexibility and homogenous borrowing costs across the EMU have resulted in continued high unemployment and disparities in real exchange rates that cannot be met by nominal revaluations (1).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>