<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archives on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archives on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Newton&#39;s Stock Market</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/newtons-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/newtons-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>Natural sciences in usual circumstances are wonderfully predictable; what goes up must come down. Economists since Walras have been promoting the profitable illusion that economics is a natural science. Today, more than anytime in history, that charade is obviously bunk. US stocks have gone up but not down. This has analysts, traders, economists, and pretty much everyone else asking the same questions. Why aren&#39;t they coming down? When will they? Should I buy US stocks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smaller Trade Deals, More Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</guid>
      <description>Rarely have free trade debaters--on all sides--had better opportunities to wag tongues. The long-standing era of free trade deals that in Canada started with the Canada-US Free Trade Agreement in 1987 (CUSFTA), superseded by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) in 1994, has run squarely into a pronounced US protectionist revival that glaringly threatens the now deeply integrated global trade regime. This is not, by the way, an uncontested protectionist movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Harry Met Sally</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/time-value-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/time-value-of-money/</guid>
      <description>What is the Best Age To Invest? According to value investors, like Warren Buffet, the secret sauce of finance can be explained in five simple words:
Investing is all about timing. The five simple words that contain the secret to investing like a billionaire are: The time value of money. While money doesn&#39;t exactly grow on trees, it does actually grow like a tree-a big, green, Christmasy [acceptable?], money tree. Yes, most people eventually learn the sheer power of savings and compound interest, but few people learn it early enough to use it wisely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt: Attractive, But Not Without Its Downsides</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/cobalt-attractive-but-not-without-its-downsides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/cobalt-attractive-but-not-without-its-downsides/</guid>
      <description>The price of a metric ton of cobalt, the precious metal used in lithium batteries, increased 60% in the last year to $81,500 USD, a 264% increase since its all time low in February of 2016. Higher prices have lifted present valuations of cobalt bearing properties and attracted capital into the metal. Typically, when a commodity booms in price supply increases until the price falls. In 2017, however, analysts predicted high prices through 2022, based on supply-side restrictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is An ETF?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-an-etf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-an-etf/</guid>
      <description>What is an ETF? Electronically traded funds are close-end funds that trade on a stock exchange. They are managed through a creation and redemption scheme that ties their contents to those of an index, or selection of investments that meet specific criteria. The value of an ETF is determined by market forces. When the value deviates from the net asset value (NAV) of the underlying investments, traders trade on the arbitrage opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I stay Or Should I Go?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/should-i-stay-or-should-i-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/should-i-stay-or-should-i-go/</guid>
      <description>Despite what some people will tell you, the recent sell-off in the stock market was not a result of rising bond yields (as I said before rising bond yields are more likely to have delayed the sell-off). Yes, bond yields now are more volatile, and so are stocks; and yes, money moving between the two and from the sidelines has an impact on that volatility; but, there are two stronger theories, in my opinion, explaining the sell-off now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Links</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/blog-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/blog-links/</guid>
      <description>Ben Bernake&amp;rsquo;s Blog
CEPR BLOG
Central Bank News
Paul Krugman New York Times
Dr. Ed&amp;rsquo;s Blog
Econ Browser
Equitable Growth
Guru Focus
Lazy Economist
Liberty Street Economics
Macro Blog Fed Atlanta
Money Beat
Multiplier Effect
Grumpy Economist
Vox
Zauzel 100
Zero Hedge
Naked Capitalism</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Links</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-links/</guid>
      <description>Bank of International Settlements
Bureau of Economic Analysis
Euro Stat
FRED
IMF
OECD
UN Data
World Bank
Stats Canada
25 million outdated data sets from google</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/principles/</guid>
      <description>It is honorable to respect all peoples, given they are not acting outside the social contract, nor seeking to usurp unjustly another&#39;s rights or freedoms.
The law protects people in societies and enables societies to function. To the extent it remains to do so, it should be upheld at every turn. When there are laws that do not serve all citizens in a society equally, those laws should be challenged and amended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Krugman Weighs In On Bernie Sanders Here:</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/paul-krugman-weighs-in-on-bernie-sanders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/paul-krugman-weighs-in-on-bernie-sanders/</guid>
      <description>There is a 90% chance Hillary will win the Democratic nomination, Paul Krugman says, so Bernie has a responsibility to support Democrats and go easier on Hillary. Paul Krugman, &amp;ldquo;Feel The Math&amp;rdquo;
This is a tell-tale sign America as an institution is standing around scratching its head about the Bernie problem. What happens if Bernie hits the tipping point?
Here&#39;s what happens if Bernie Sanders goes to the White House: America stops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data And Output, The Second Wave</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-and-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-and-output/</guid>
      <description>The communications revolution is no longer promising to shift production possibility frontiers outwardly, it is doing so rapidly. But there is a second shift we have not seen yet, and that&#39;s the big data shift. The capacity for organizations to improve decisions by rendering the changing digital footprint into meaningful direction, is going to reduce economic distortions in a number of ways. Firms will be able to match customers with products more efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Government And The Data Revolution</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smart-government-and-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smart-government-and-big-data/</guid>
      <description>The data revolution is impacting government in a number of ways. The foremost is known as &#39;smart government&#39;, which is a reference to the way governments manage the data they have and the way they make that management and the services that go with it available to their clients (constituents in a democracy). The second impact, also intelligent, is known as the &#39;smart city.&#39;
Smart government is a concept championed by the Estonian government (our example), which won the United Nations Public Service Award, in the category of Promoting Whole of Government Approaches in the Information Age, for their online business registry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research, The New Profit Center</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/research-new-profit-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/research-new-profit-center/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced financial regulation typically comes with intended and unintended consequences. Directive 2004/39/EC, the Market for Financial Instruments Directive (MiFID), for example, successfully increased competition among financial instrument trading organizations in Europe. This brought down consumer prices and narrowed margins. It also sent market participants looking to move large blocks of shares into dark pools, where trade data are not made public.
There will be intended and unintended consequences from MiFID&#39;s successor, MiFID2, which is anticipated to be in effect by January 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Psychology</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/organizational-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/organizational-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Numerous studies have examined what intangible and tangible factors might cause one organization to outperform others over a period of time. There is no question that ideas and talent are invaluable, but it is no longer any surprise that the single most important factor affecting organizational performance is organizational psychology. Here are a few examples:
Ray Dalio runs Bridgewater Associates, one of the largest hedge funds in the world. In Connecticut, he&#39;s got 1500 people, some of whom are the best and brightest brains in the financial sector, but does Ray cite his PhDs, research acumen, and process as his number one a comparative advantage?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science And The Law</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-science-and-the-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-science-and-the-law/</guid>
      <description>Information technologies and the data they create are changing the world rapidly in a multitude of ways. The legal profession, one of the most traditional and adverse to change, is beginning to adapt. A new breed of data savvy lawyers are entering legal circles everywhere and bringing with them an inertia from new technologies.
Firstly, the legal profession stands to gain from those data driven insights that are common across organizations, like more accurately targeted marketing, more informed case selection, more efficient internal procedures, and pricing models that minimize both losses of producer surplus, and dead-weight losses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet Of Things</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/the-internet-of-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/the-internet-of-things/</guid>
      <description>The Internet of things (IOT) is a reference to computerization in devices and machines we use in everyday life. Smart homes and the smart appliances in them are examples of things that are more and more frequently connected to the Internet and programmable with computers. Online appliances transmit sensory information upstream to computer processors that make decisions, like adjusting the heat, turning on or off a hot water tank, switching up power sources, or charging electronic devices, like cars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Statistics And Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>National and international level statistics that report macroeconomic indicators, like nominal and real inflation, international transaction flows, and trade statistics, are relied on by market participants, policy makers and stakeholders as inputs to critical decisions. More often than not, macroeconomic statistics are taken as reliable, after-all, those are our official statistics, right?. But just how reliable are they? Unfortunately, the answer is that aligning statistics with underlying realities is a challenging task, and mainstream macroeconomic statistics should, even in the best of cases, be taken with a grain of salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Firms Big Decisions</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-needs-and-firm-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-needs-and-firm-size/</guid>
      <description>Big data means billions if not trillions of observations recorded daily. Sophisticated data infrastructures and advanced algorithms reveal new insights into our fast changing world, but only for those massive organizations with the transaction frequency and the know how to extract them, right?
The question is one of relevance. While big data benefits for large organizations are readily tangible--like in the case where retailers want to know when customers are more likely to purchase which products, or what optimal prices will move discounted products in a set time frame--smaller organizations sometimes just don&#39;t see how the data revolution is important to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research In The Age Of Data Science</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-science-and-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-science-and-research/</guid>
      <description>Data science improves organizational function, but it isn&#39;t always cheap. Scientific data analysis enables organizations to develop more internally efficient business systems. They can more easily reach potential stakeholders and engage them. Data informed organizations can prepare forward, more accurately refine and refocus strategies, and more effectively manage risks. The problem is data science itself is an investment heavy human resource, and those costs are passed on to the employer. Trainees need a strong background in probability and statistics, and expertise in a speciality subject, like political science, medicine, engineering, or economics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Economic Policy</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-economic-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-economic-policy/</guid>
      <description>What is economic policy? If economics can be described as the study of the allocation of scarce resources among agents, economic policy can be described as the public rules and regulations that guide that allocation. Wherever a society is governed with laws, there will be laws that influence the economic prosperity of constituents, producers, and suppliers, as well as the distribution of resources among agents within the economy. Those rules constitute economic policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Maths Programming</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-maths-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-maths-programming/</guid>
      <description>What is maths programming? Mathematical programming, or computational programming, is the process of translating mathematically representable problems into computer languages then harnessing the power of computers to solve them. Along with the Internet, and task facilitation, mathematical programming is probably the most important contribution from the modern computer to human evolution. There are many kinds of mathematical programming techniques. Among these are: linear and non-linear programming, integer programming, mixed complementary problems, networks, goal programming, multiple objective optimization, queuing theory, regression analysis, and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Decision Analysis</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-decision-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-decision-analysis/</guid>
      <description>What is decision analysis? Decision analysis is a subcategory of decision science. Ultimately, all data science could be classified as decision science, because the entire point of data analytics and informatics is to enable better decision making processes to yield better outcomes from decisions. While decision science and decision analysis cannot eliminate the possibility of sub-optimal outcomes, they are in themselves useful if not mandatory processes. They can, for example, enable teams or decision makers to move forward with confidence in their assessments of decision variable behaviour across decision parameters, and thus with more reasonable expectation of probable outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Optimization</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-optimization/</guid>
      <description>What is optimization Optimization is about making choices that lead to first best outcomes. Mathematically, optimization is usually described with differential calculus, though when functions are linear, and problems are adequately fit substitution can lead to optimal solutions. In mathematics, optimization first requires the delineation of an objective function, a dependent function meant to be maximized or minimized through variations in the independent functions that predict it. Solving optimization problems therefore requires identifying maximum or minimum points on the objective function and qualifying those points as local or global maximums or minimums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Macroeconomics</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-are-macroeconomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-are-macroeconomics/</guid>
      <description>What is macroeconomics Macroeconomics is the field of economics that deals with aggregated quantities. Microeconomics, for example, might deal with firm level economics, while macroeconomics might deal with aggregate firms level economics, the economics of all the firms in an economy together. Macroeconomics therefore includes the study of national level and supranational level economics.
What kind of indicators are macroeconomic? Macroeconomic indicators include trade indicators, like the trade balance, and trade openness, but also indicators that describe other facets of the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is International Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-international-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-international-trade/</guid>
      <description>What is international trade? International trade is the movement of goods across national borders. Because bilateral exchange rates change frequently, international trade is watched closely by national and supranational governments. Small changes in currency pair spreads can impact the movement of goods across borders and, as a consequence, the health of a nation&#39;s domestic industry and its employment levels.
How do organizations measure international trade? Physical goods (commodity trade) are tracked by governments when they enter various economic and trade zones within an economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Modelling</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-modelling/</guid>
      <description>What is modelling? Modelling is an important part of decision science. Modellers make simplified representations of reality to produce judgements about reality and guide real decisions. Models can be abstract and theoretical, or data driven and empirical. Both categories can be prescriptive, predictive, or descriptive.
Why model? Modelling is a cost-effective way to test the successes and failures of potential projects without committing large-scale resources. Modelling is also useful as means of building support necessary to successfully launch projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are Statistics</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-are-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-are-statistics/</guid>
      <description>What are statistics? Statistics are transformations of data through calculation. While in theory any calculation done with data yields a statistic, in practice statistics are associated with scientific and field specific calculations. For example, during preparation phase your data is frequently explored and analysed using simple plotting techniques that present meaningful descriptive statistics from the data or data subset, like the mean, median, and/or quartile ranges. As another example, in macroeconomics, various calculations with data yield well known statistics like GDP, inflation, or trade balance by sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Data Wrangling</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-data-wrangling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-data-wrangling/</guid>
      <description>What is data wrangling? Data wrangling is the process of preparing data for analysis or computation. It includes transforming data into various formats and statistical derivations, cleaning data to account for missing observations, clumsy data types, or outright errors, and arranging data into workable categorized data sets.
When should data be cleaned? Anyone working with data knows it needs to be cleaned many times along the data pipeline. After data is collected, it must be wrangled before it is stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Data Science</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-data-science/</guid>
      <description>What is data science? The science of data promises to change the world, but many of us do not know what data science is. This segement gives you our answer.
Data science is the science of data analytics in the context of scientific query. The data scientist first asks scientific questions, then gathers data relevant to those questions, and finally applies a variety of computer processes and statistical and probabilistic theories to derive answers to those questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is The Money?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/where-is-the-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/where-is-the-money/</guid>
      <description>As Krugman might say, &#34;...it&#39;s in the market, stupid.&#34; The most influential economy in the world is poised to raise interest rates, but not because of inflation. Central banks in major parts of the world are still at the zero bound, and core prices are behaving as they should when targeted only because liquidity is trapped on balance sheets as inventory. What happened? Why did monetary easing take half a decade to jump-start the US dollar economy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BIS Warns of Low Rates</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bis-warns-of-low-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bis-warns-of-low-rates/</guid>
      <description>The Bank of International Settlements (BIS) continues to reprimand contemporary central banking culture for easy money fixes it argues feed instability by creating global economic conditions that foster bubbles. As the story goes, demand side policies are band-aids slapped on top of deep structural wounds. This is especially the case in a world where financial intermediation dominates money channels with a vast array of levers, ropes, and pulleys that push the lag between easing and higher demand more and more unmeasurably into the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Raise or Not to Raise</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</guid>
      <description>US indicators out this week, like the Chicago PMI and the CPI estimates, support both sides of a US turn-around, the output side and the consumption side. Yet still the FED, though widely expected to raise rates in the summer, remains tight-lipped about it, downplaying positive economic indicators. This sounds like policy speak for &#39;we want to keep the option in our pocket,&#39; and there is good reason. While the UK and the US have been running the money tap seemingly forever, at least since 1929 part-two, the great depression strikes back, the rest of the known world, and the unknown world, is starting to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming ECB Rate Changes</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday&#39;s flash Harmonized Consumer Price Index indicated a drop in EMU price rises to 0.5%. Given the ECB&#39;s primary target is price stability, markets are widely anticipating tomorrow&#39;s ECB meeting will see overnight interest rates reduced to negative levels.This would have banks less likely to deposit daily surpluses in the ECB overnight and more likely to loan them out. They would also commit a smaller portion of liquidity to paying down liabilities previously acquired with the ECB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Outlook</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/macroeconomic-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/macroeconomic-outlook/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The following article comprises my general world economic outlook. It is necessary to clarify a few points for the reader. Firstly, the exercise is positive rather than normative. For example, any mention of oil should be read as an inchoate view of where world oil prices, or supply and demand, may go in future periods, rather than a statement that policies should pursue increased oil output, or that carbon fuel consumption is net surplus enhancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics Of A Winner</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/characteristics-of-a-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/characteristics-of-a-winner/</guid>
      <description>Innovative Hard working Believes in what he/she is doing Focuses on details Maintains a calm and relaxed presence Well spoken (concise&amp;hellip;excellent word choice) In-it-to-win-it Responsible Intelligent Continually developing Keeps moving to the front Gets as much perspective as possible Accepts where he/she is at Lets go of errors Genuine Thorough Dutiful Light-hearted, fun Prepared Attentive Implements systems for thoughts and actions Takes action as often as possible Creative Prioritizes actions to optimal Makes time for relationships Presents value and credentials when criticized Expects attacks from others but does not hold this against them Doesn&amp;rsquo;t take life personally Courteous Engages with different social groups without owning differences Maintains a well tuned psychology Limits unprepared actions Integrates self-checking processes Keeps a narrow focus to maintain effectiveness Doesn&amp;rsquo;t flinch at criticism (nor own it) Doesn&amp;rsquo;t spin, stretch the truth or lie Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sink to a lower level Accepts the behaviour of others with humour keen Discusses what successful actions he/she is doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Optimal Pathway To Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</guid>
      <description>In the aftermath of the global financial crisis, intrinsic political and economic challenges have raised questions about the survival of the European Monetary Union (EMU). To the extent that we can view the crisis as an asymmetric employment shock, we are reminded that national level barriers to labour mobility do not make for strong optimal currency area arguments. In addition, price level inflexibility and homogenous borrowing costs across the EMU have resulted in continued high unemployment and disparities in real exchange rates that cannot be met by nominal revaluations (1).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress: Getting Along In Life</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/getting-along-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/getting-along-in-life/</guid>
      <description>Inspiration is about being on the upswing. Find out what gets you there, find out what keeps you there, and make a habit of it. Success is about a good nights sleep, either tomorrow is Sunday or you are prepared to meet it. Self-improvement is a lifestyle. Expectations are so yesterday. Grey area is dangerous. Make sure you spell it out. Prodigality is tiresome. Habits are the measuring stick you are looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Dollar Could Be Good For Canada</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-the-euro-in-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-the-euro-in-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>Pundits of the double-dip recession theory cite the now globally anticipated fallout of the U.S. dollar as a key source. The fed is printing money like confetti, they say. The U.S. Treasury bill bubble is soon to pop, they add. The newly coined (U.S. dollar-carry trade) (it used to be the yen-carry trade) is driving commodities through the roof, they squeal. The concerns are many. For example, rampant increases in U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill That Sank Ignatieff Looks Likely to Float</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bill-sank-ignatieff-likely-to-float/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bill-sank-ignatieff-likely-to-float/</guid>
      <description>Remember last October? Under Stephane Dion, the Liberals were, by no small margin, consistently behind the Conservatives in the national public opinion polls. Then the Conservatives released their economic update and political mayhem ensued. Stephane, Jack and Gille went up the hill and planned a coalition coupe. Stephan Harper set a frighteningly partisan political precedent by proroguing parliament when the conservatives were facing an election they looked likely to lose. And, after Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing With The HST</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/dealing-with-the-hst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/dealing-with-the-hst/</guid>
      <description>Protests across the province last month made it clear to British Columbians that the PST/GST harmonization announced on July 23 by Premier Gordon Campbell is not going over well. Former Premier Bill Vander Zalm grasped onto the issue like a life raft, presumably hoping to resurrect his long-thought dead but apparently still alive Social Credit initiatives. The NDP are joining Mr. Vander Zalm in the attack on the provincial Liberal for, perhaps, partisan reasons (it&#39;s worth nothing that New Democrats in prairies support the HST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Down The House</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bringing-down-the-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bringing-down-the-house/</guid>
      <description>What ever happened to Canadian government for all Canadians? Clearly out the window. Whatever happened to non-partisan politics? Has there ever been such a thing? Do we really need an economic stimulus package, or is the recent uproar in the House of Commons little more than partisan on partisan? Will a coalition government serve the people well? Is democracy being put to the test?
Well, it&#39;s not much, but technically an increase in newspaper sales should cause an increase in GDP, and if one opens the paper it&#39;s hard not to imagine an increase in newspaper sales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Bell, Business And State Tie The knot.</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/wedding-bells-business-and-state-tie-the-knot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/wedding-bells-business-and-state-tie-the-knot/</guid>
      <description>Last month, before U.S. election results, I was chatting with a friend about economic political history. He wrote a line that stuck with me. He wrote (Western civilization has got to stop patting itself on the back for separating church and state and get on with the business of separating business and state.) At the time I thought the line might one day just come off (I was thinking of receding lobbyist influence given the likelihood of a democrat government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Debate Revisited</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/the-great-debate-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/the-great-debate-revisited/</guid>
      <description>Okay, Obama is in the news, he&#39;s made friends, he&#39;s made headlines, he&#39;s made history-he&#39;s everywhere. The world stands in awe. Democracy has been authenticated. It&#39;s no longer a form of government that claims to champion the cause of the marginalized while craftily concealing the domination of the under-privileged by autocrats and oligarchs---it&#39;s the real the thing: true government by popular representation.
And it&#39;s clear that people view Obama as a human being--- someone with a conscience, who believes that America stands for democracy, liberty, freedom, and the rule of law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Tories At The Table, More Water In The Liberal Hull</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/more-tories-at-the-table-more-water-in-the-liberal-hull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/more-tories-at-the-table-more-water-in-the-liberal-hull/</guid>
      <description>Was it Warren Buffet who reminded us of the irrationality in the stock market? What was it he said, stock markets are people driven and people are irrational? I&#39;d like to add the movements of populist governments to his irrational people bit as, it seems to me, both populist governments and stock markets are guided by public opinion. If public opinion is an expression of human behavior, (run that one by your local shrink if you like,) does that make it the result of feelings, instincts, and herd-like responses to media induced perceptions (not a herd of hippo&#39;s mind you, that&#39;s the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stimulating Interest</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/stimulating-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/stimulating-interest/</guid>
      <description>So world leaders (note: 20 of them) have agreed to come together in a first ever meeting of the G20 to discuss a restructuring of global financial market systems. Finally, economic and politically minded people everywhere are revisiting the decisions that have shaped our global economy into the fertile soil for crisis that it has become.
Milton Friedman&#39;s legacy is under attack. The concepts of nationalism and socialism in the state are not only being reconsidered, they are being re-instituted as we speak (the nationalization of big banks globally).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallstreet&#39;s Liquidity Problem</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</guid>
      <description>It doesn&#39;t take a rocket scientist to see that addressing the liquidity problem on Wall Street by borrowing to restore the ability to lend does not address the underlying aggregate debt issue.
The common sense approach says that to avoid a sudden crash or some kind of long drawn out debt deflation, the American Government needs to address the ability of the real economy to earn, borrow and spend. And in this sense yes, much of the relief could have gone to debtors at large and not the creditors, who to pay their new debts will have to lend more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>