<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macroeconomics on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/macroeconomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Macroeconomics on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/macroeconomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BIS Warns of Low Rates</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</guid>
      <description>The Bank of International Settlements (BIS) continues to reprimand contemporary central banking culture for easy money fixes it argues feed instability by creating global economic conditions that foster bubbles. As the story goes, demand side policies are band-aids slapped on top of deep structural wounds. This is especially the case in a world where financial intermediation dominates money channels with a vast array of levers, ropes, and pulleys that push the lag between easing and higher demand more and more unmeasurably into the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case for Continued Pursuit of Emu Accession in Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper reviews a variety of academic publications, including those from authors who produced gravity models, and presents trade arguments for and against Lithuanian accession to the European Monetary Union (EMU). While the results prompt the author to argue in favour of accession, there is no commentary on either the benefits of reduced default risk or the costs of potential negative externalities like declines in living conditions or increased brain drain and population exodus that could result if accession causes tax increases, higher unemployment or lowered government expenditure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>