<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Macroeconomics on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/macroeconomics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Macroeconomics on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/macroeconomics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Newton&#39;s Stock Market</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-newtons-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-newtons-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>Natural sciences in usual circumstances are wonderfully predictable; what goes up must come down. Economists since Walras have been promoting the profitable illusion that economics is a natural science. Today, more than anytime in history, that charade is obviously bunk. US stocks have gone up but not down. This has analysts, traders, economists, and pretty much everyone else asking the same questions. Why aren&#39;t they coming down? When will they? Should I buy US stocks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smaller Trade Deals, More Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</guid>
      <description>Rarely have free trade debaters--on all sides--had better opportunities to wag tongues. The long-standing era of free trade deals that in Canada started with the Canada-US Free Trade Agreement in 1987 (CUSFTA), superseded by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) in 1994, has run squarely into a pronounced US protectionist revival that glaringly threatens the now deeply integrated global trade regime. This is not, by the way, an uncontested protectionist movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Macroeconomics</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-19-what-are-macroeconomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-19-what-are-macroeconomics/</guid>
      <description>What is macroeconomics Macroeconomics is the field of economics that deals with aggregated quantities. Microeconomics, for example, might deal with firm level economics, while macroeconomics might deal with aggregate firms level economics, the economics of all the firms in an economy together. Macroeconomics therefore includes the study of national level and supranational level economics.
What kind of indicators are macroeconomic? Macroeconomic indicators include trade indicators, like the trade balance, and trade openness, but also indicators that describe other facets of the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is The Money?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-12-03-where-is-the-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-12-03-where-is-the-money/</guid>
      <description>As Krugman might say, &#34;...it&#39;s in the market, stupid.&#34; The most influential economy in the world is poised to raise interest rates, but not because of inflation. Central banks in major parts of the world are still at the zero bound, and core prices are behaving as they should when targeted only because liquidity is trapped on balance sheets as inventory. What happened? Why did monetary easing take half a decade to jump-start the US dollar economy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BIS Warns of Low Rates</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</guid>
      <description>The Bank of International Settlements (BIS) continues to reprimand contemporary central banking culture for easy money fixes it argues feed instability by creating global economic conditions that foster bubbles. As the story goes, demand side policies are band-aids slapped on top of deep structural wounds. This is especially the case in a world where financial intermediation dominates money channels with a vast array of levers, ropes, and pulleys that push the lag between easing and higher demand more and more unmeasurably into the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Raise or Not to Raise</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-02-26-to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-02-26-to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</guid>
      <description>US indicators out this week, like the Chicago PMI and the CPI estimates, support both sides of a US turn-around, the output side and the consumption side. Yet still the FED, though widely expected to raise rates in the summer, remains tight-lipped about it, downplaying positive economic indicators. This sounds like policy speak for &#39;we want to keep the option in our pocket,&#39; and there is good reason. While the UK and the US have been running the money tap seemingly forever, at least since 1929 part-two, the great depression strikes back, the rest of the known world, and the unknown world, is starting to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming ECB Rate Changes</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2014-06-04-upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2014-06-04-upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday&#39;s flash Harmonized Consumer Price Index indicated a drop in EMU price rises to 0.5%. Given the ECB&#39;s primary target is price stability, markets are widely anticipating tomorrow&#39;s ECB meeting will see overnight interest rates reduced to negative levels.This would have banks less likely to deposit daily surpluses in the ECB overnight and more likely to loan them out. They would also commit a smaller portion of liquidity to paying down liabilities previously acquired with the ECB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Outlook</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-08-14-macroeconomic-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-08-14-macroeconomic-outlook/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The following article comprises my general world economic outlook. It is necessary to clarify a few points for the reader. Firstly, the exercise is positive rather than normative. For example, any mention of oil should be read as an inchoate view of where world oil prices, or supply and demand, may go in future periods, rather than a statement that policies should pursue increased oil output, or that carbon fuel consumption is net surplus enhancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Union Government Procurement Study</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-03-28-european-union-government-procurement-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-03-28-european-union-government-procurement-study/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This report analyzes EU-wide public procurement markets and market segments through modelling of the EU&amp;rsquo;s Tenders Electronic Daily (TED) data, among other sources, as well as the critical legal elements of the emerging EU-wide public procurement regime. The modelling results point to procurement markets that are particularly contestable for Canadian Companies. In the fast changing world of public procurement, the work in this paper is no longer relevant, but does provide sources for future research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EU Canada Comprehensive Economic and Trade Agreement</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-07-eu-canada-ceta-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-07-eu-canada-ceta-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Abstract An analysis of procurement laws and statistics at the major levels of government across Canada. Data collection, wrangling, modelling, research, writing, and editing by Yuri Tricys, among others. Author and Director of research, Kurt Hubner.   
Download EU Canada CETA Workshop</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case for Continued Pursuit of Emu Accession in Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper reviews arguments in academic literature for and against Lithuania&amp;rsquo;s pursuit of EMU accession. The results indicate Lithuania stands to gain in trade with ROW and with the EMU on completion of change-over to the Euro. Moreover, trade specialization and the potential of under-trading, promise further gains from Euro accession. Economies of scale ensure that gains from trade and currency management cost reductions will be large relative to GDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Optimal Pathway To Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper reviews academic arguments for and against fiscal policy alignment and increased transnational budgets in the EMU. It suggests credit market instruments are costlier than tax based transfers and the current system of structural funding is inadequate,and an enhanced fiscal transfer system, funded from a community level tax base, is an optimal pathway toward business cycle convergence in the EMU.    Download Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Dollar Could Be Good For Canada</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-11-28-strong-dollar-could-be-good-for-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-11-28-strong-dollar-could-be-good-for-canada/</guid>
      <description>Pundits of the double-dip recession theory cite the now globally anticipated fallout of the U.S. dollar as a key source. The fed is printing money like confetti, they say. The U.S. Treasury bill bubble is soon to pop, they add. The newly coined (U.S. dollar-carry trade) (it used to be the yen-carry trade) is driving commodities through the roof, they squeal. The concerns are many. For example, rampant increases in U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallstreet&#39;s Liquidity Problem</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-22-wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-22-wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</guid>
      <description>It doesn&#39;t take a rocket scientist to see that addressing the liquidity problem on Wall Street by borrowing to restore the ability to lend does not address the underlying aggregate debt issue.
The common sense approach says that to avoid a sudden crash or some kind of long drawn out debt deflation, the American Government needs to address the ability of the real economy to earn, borrow and spend. And in this sense yes, much of the relief could have gone to debtors at large and not the creditors, who to pay their new debts will have to lend more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>