<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Motivations on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Motivations on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Alignment Through Communication</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-01-30-achieving-alignment-through-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-01-30-achieving-alignment-through-communication/</guid>
      <description>Psychologists do important work, but it doesn&#39;t take one to know that people operate a lot like computers. We&#39;ve got code inside that issues a response when stimulated. The more you know the person, the more you know what responses to expect. In any organization team building improves organizational outcomes. But what is going on when team members bond?
Alignment is a concept that explains what&#39;s going on. Let each line in this chart represent a person; but more than that, let it represent their psychology, the millions of associations their mind contains between images and expectations, words and definitions, and information and responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Moves Habits Tell You Where</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-15-life-moves-habits-tell-you-where/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-15-life-moves-habits-tell-you-where/</guid>
      <description>Habits can be bad, like when they deter progress toward your current set of goals, and they can be good, like when they move you closer to your goals or align you with them (if, for example, your goal is to attain a certain state of being). Habits include things like the way you spend your time, the way you think about things, and the way you communicate. They determine where you are going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bean Machine</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-07-the-bean-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-07-the-bean-machine/</guid>
      <description>Staying Focused On Being Yourself Here is something to think about. What does it mean to be normal?
The picture below is a picture of a bean machine,  also known as a Quincunx,  a Dalton Board,  or Plinko. 
What happens to the ball when it gets dropped into the top of the bean machine? It gets bounced around right? Does the ball get to choose in which slot it will end up?</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>