<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>academic on Cloud Nine</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/academic/</link><description>Recent content in academic on Cloud Nine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/academic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>European Union Government Procurement Study</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-03-28-european-union-government-procurement-study/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-03-28-european-union-government-procurement-study/</guid><description>Abstract
This report analyzes EU-wide public procurement markets and market segments through modelling of
the EU's Tenders Electronic Daily (TED) data, among other sources, as well as the critical legal elements of the emerging EU-wide public
procurement regime. The modelling results point to procurement markets that are particularly contestable for Canadian Companies. In the fast changing world of public procurement,
the work in this paper is no longer relevant, but does provide sources for future research.</description></item><item><title>EU Canada Comprehensive Economic and Trade Agreement</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-07-eu-canada-ceta-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-07-eu-canada-ceta-workshop/</guid><description>Abstract
An analysis of procurement laws and statistics at the major levels of government across Canada.
Data collection, wrangling, modelling, research, writing, and editing by Yuri Tricys, among others. Author and Director of research, Kurt Hubner.
Download EU Canada CETA Workshop</description></item><item><title>Trade Liberalization And Sector Productivity</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</guid><description>Abstract
This paper analyzes the effects of trade liberalization on productivity at the sector level. This is
done with a multivariable regression of relative gross labour productivity on sector trade, between the
U.S. and Canada, relative to total trade, between Canada and the world. A set of before and after
treatment variables are used to distinguish the difference between the effect of trade openness before
the NAFTA preferential trade agreement and after the agreement.</description></item><item><title>A Case for Continued Pursuit of Emu Accession in Lithuania</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</guid><description>Abstract
This paper reviews arguments in academic literature for and against Lithuania's pursuit of EMU accession. The
results indicate Lithuania stands to gain in trade with ROW and with the EMU on completion of change-over to the Euro. Moreover, trade
specialization and the potential of under-trading, promise further gains from Euro accession. Economies of scale ensure that gains from
trade and currency management cost reductions will be large relative to GDP.</description></item><item><title>An Optimal Pathway To Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</guid><description>Abstract
This paper reviews academic arguments for and against fiscal policy alignment and increased transnational budgets in the EMU. It suggests
credit market instruments are costlier than tax based transfers and the current system of structural funding is inadequate,and an enhanced
fiscal transfer system, funded from a community level tax base, is an optimal pathway toward business cycle convergence in the EMU.
Download Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</description></item></channel></rss>