<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>trends global on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/trends-global/</link>
    <description>Recent content in trends global on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/trends-global/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Newton&#39;s Stock Market</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-newtons-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-newtons-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>Naturalsciences in usual circumstances are wonderfully predictable; what goes up must come down. Economists since Walras have beenpromoting the profitable illusion that economics is a natural science. Today, more than anytime in history, that charade is obviously bunk.US stocks have gone up but not down. This has analysts, traders, economists, and pretty much everyone else asking the same questions. Whyaren&#39;t they coming down? When will they? Should I buy US stocks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smaller Trade Deals, More Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</guid>
      <description>Rarely havefree trade debaters--on all sides--had better opportunities to wag tongues. The long-standing era of free trade deals that in Canada startedwith the Canada-US Free Trade Agreement in 1987 (CUSFTA), superseded by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) in 1994, has runsquarely into a pronounced US protectionist revival that glaringly threatens the now deeply integrated global trade regime. This is not, bythe way, an uncontested protectionist movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt: Attractive, But Not Without Its Downsides</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-20-cobalt-attractive-not-without-downsides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-20-cobalt-attractive-not-without-downsides/</guid>
      <description>The price of a metric ton of cobalt, the precious metal used in lithium batteries, increased 60% in the last year to $81,500USD, a 264% increase since its all time low in February of 2016. Higher prices have lifted present valuations of cobalt bearing propertiesand attracted capital into the metal. Typically, when a commodity booms in price supply increases until the price falls. In 2017, however,analysts predicted high prices through 2022, based on supply-side restrictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I stay Or Should I Go?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-12-should-i-stay-or-should-i-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-12-should-i-stay-or-should-i-go/</guid>
      <description>Despite whatsome people will tell you, the recent sell-off in the stock market was not a result of rising bond yields (as I said before rising bondyields are more likely to have delayed the sell-off). Yes, bond yields now are more volatile, and so are stocks; and yes, money movingbetween the two and from the sidelines has an impact on that volatility; but, there are two stronger theories, in my opinion, explaining thesell-off now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Krugman Weighs In On Bernie Sanders Here:</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-04-02-paul-krugman-weighs-in-on-bernie-sanders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-04-02-paul-krugman-weighs-in-on-bernie-sanders/</guid>
      <description>There is a 90% chance Hillary will win the Democratic nomination, Paul Krugman says, so Bernie has a responsibility to support Democrats and go easier on Hillary.Paul Krugman, &amp;ldquo;Feel The Math&amp;quot;
This is a tell-tale sign America as an institution is standing around scratching its head about the Bernie problem. What happens if Bernie hits the tipping point?
Here&#39;s what happens if Bernie Sanders goes to the White House: America stops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is The Money?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-12-03-where-is-the-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-12-03-where-is-the-money/</guid>
      <description>As Krugman might say, &#34;...it&#39;s in the market, stupid.&#34; The most influential economy in the world is poised to raiseinterest rates, but not because of inflation. Central banks in major parts of the world are still at the zero bound, and core prices arebehaving as they should when targeted only because liquidity is trapped on balance sheets as inventory. What happened? Why did monetaryeasing take half a decade to jump-start the US dollar economy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BIS Warns of Low Rates</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</guid>
      <description>The Bank of International Settlements (BIS) continues to reprimand contemporary central banking culture for easy moneyfixes it argues feed instability by creating global economic conditions that foster bubbles. As the story goes, demand side policies areband-aids slapped on top of deep structural wounds. This is especially the case in a world where financial intermediation dominates moneychannels with a vast array of levers, ropes, and pulleys that push the lag between easing and higher demand more and more unmeasurably intothe future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Raise or Not to Raise</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-02-26-to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-02-26-to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</guid>
      <description>US indicators out this week, like the Chicago PMI and the CPI estimates, support both sides of a US turn-around, the output side and theconsumption side. Yet still the FED, though widely expected to raise rates in the summer, remains tight-lipped about it, downplayingpositive economic indicators. This sounds like policy speak for &#39;we want to keep the option in our pocket,&#39; and there is good reason. While the UK and the US have been running the money tap seemingly forever, at least since 1929 part-two, the great depression strikes back,the rest of the known world, and the unknown world, is starting to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming ECB Rate Changes</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2014-06-04-upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2014-06-04-upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday&#39;s flash Harmonized Consumer Price Index indicated a drop in EMU price rises to 0.5%. Given the ECB&#39;s primary target is pricestability, markets are widely anticipating tomorrow&#39;s ECB meeting will see overnight interest rates reduced to negative levels.This wouldhave banks less likely to deposit daily surpluses in the ECB overnight and more likely to loan them out. They would also commit a smallerportion of liquidity to paying down liabilities previously acquired with the ECB.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>