<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Cloud Nine</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/</link><description>Recent content on Cloud Nine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Citadel, by Algis Budrys</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-04-07-citadel-algis-budrys/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-04-07-citadel-algis-budrys/</guid><description>Algis Budrys, was a wonderful Science Fiction author from back in the
day, when men wanted to land on the moon and science fiction was the latest greatest thing. When I was a teenager, I found a story of his in a magazine my father
had been reading. His name was circled in pen. My father didn't tell war stories, or talk about being Lithuanian, but I found signs of
Lithuanianism everywhere - and my dad had a thing for science fiction.</description></item><item><title>Dune, by Frank Herbert</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-04-07-dune-frank-herbert/</link><pubDate>Tue, 07 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-04-07-dune-frank-herbert/</guid><description>Dune, undoubtedly one of the best science fiction series ever written, is scheduled to return to the screen this
November (2020). No film has yet done the book justice, in any way. It was the first of it's kind. A truly sprawling science fiction saga.
New worlds. New empires. Humans and aliens, locked together a terrific tale of espionage, science, warfare, and trade. It has all the
literary foundations for a film series to rival "</description></item><item><title>American Financier, by Jean Strous</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-28-american-financier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-28-american-financier/</guid><description>J.P. Morgan: celebrated, powerfully unambiguous, oligarchically connected, pillar of American history. The man with the bushy
furrowed brows, pudgy fat nose, and bulging adams apple. As a school boy, he was infirm, aloof, and disliked. As a business titan his stubby fingers horned on
every corner of gilded America. He built the railway to the west. When Edison dumped Tesla on the street with a shovel - less a year or two of salary - Morgan
picked him up and put him back in the money.</description></item><item><title>Written Good</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-04-written-good/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-04-written-good/</guid><description>Yesterday wasn't a typical day. It was my birthday. I took a brush to the whiteboard and replaced all the TODOs with the
words "Read Python," in an extra large blue custom font I'm calling 'meander.' I packed one of the python books in with a couple of others
and took the train to the library. My idea of a good time really is a quiet nook and a well written book.</description></item><item><title>Smith, Keynes, and Penrose</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-15-smith-keynes-and-penrose/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-15-smith-keynes-and-penrose/</guid><description>What do
Adam Smith, John Maynard Keynes, and Roger Penrose have in common? Well, certainly there must have been something, but it wasn't the content
of their books. Smith and Keynes were economists, Penrose is a mathematical physicist. Still, I've mentioned them here together because in a
way I'm telling a story and Roger Penrose's book is to me right now in some ways what Keynes's book once was. Let's start with me and Adam
Smith.</description></item><item><title>Business the Ultimate Resource</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-04-business-the-ultimate-resource/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-04-business-the-ultimate-resource/</guid><description>This is a
fantastic book. I bought it when it was first published (in 2002), and my copy is well used. The idea seems to be basically to publish
everything you need to know about business, that a book can teach you, between two covers. The reality of course is that there
are a lot of books on business, and many of them are inspiring and educational. Moreover, books like this one are great for people who want to
understand key processes in big business, and even helpful for those who want to build better small business, but, despite what Chekhov
said about it, business is not about processes, buzz words, or other people's money, it's about value exchange.</description></item></channel></rss>