<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>alternative on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/alternative/</link>
    <description>Recent content in alternative on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/alternative/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - A Wednesday Evening Alternative Playlist</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-21-music-playlist-wednesday-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-21-music-playlist-wednesday-mix/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Hello Oasis: She&amp;#39;s Electric, Little Scream: Love As A Weapon, Kevin Morby: Dorothy, Rat Head: Abbrasive, RJD2: Ghostwriter, Caravan Palace: Dramaphone, Monatik: What is Crazy About, Little Big and Tatarka: Arriba
 Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Wednesday Mix</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Some Music From The Band Weezer</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-21-music-playlist-weezer-weezer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-21-music-playlist-weezer-weezer/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Back To The Shack, Undone: Sweater Song, Say it Ain&amp;#39;t So, Hash Pipe, Hero, Go Away, My Name Is Jonas, The End of The Game, The Good Life, Beverly Hills, We Are All Drugs, Pork And Beans, Perfect Situation, King of the World, I Want You To, Buddy Holly  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;WeezerFormation and first years (1989-1994)&#34;Vocalist and guitarist Rivers Cuomo moved to Los Angeles in 1989 with his high school metal band, Avant Garde, later renamed Zoom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Lithuanian Music, Indie Rock</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-08-01-music-playlist-lithuanian-indie-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-08-01-music-playlist-lithuanian-indie-music/</guid>
      <description>Songs:No Real Pioneers - at Ymir Audio, Verslo rizikos rezervas - Mano vaikas prazilo, Verslo Rizikos Rezervas - Kur plauki?, Biplan - Labas rytas, Daddy Was A Milkman - Seasons, Empti Radio laga, Donny Montell feat. Mark Les - LEISK MYLET, FREAKS ON FLOOR: Star,Rasabasa: Interstellar, KaYra: Alligator  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Lithuanian Music</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Indie Rock, Featuring Spoon</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-07-30-music-playlist-indie-rock-spoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-07-30-music-playlist-indie-rock-spoon/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Spoon - Finer Feelings, Foster The People - Pick U Up, Datarock- Fa Fa Fa, The Zolas - Molotov Girls, the ponys - double vision, Vampire Weekend - A-Punk, Modest Mouse - Dashboard, Vampire Weekend - Cousins , Arcade Fire - No Cars Go, Belle and Sebastian - Legal Man, Vampire Weekend: A Punk, Electric Light Orchestra: Mr. Blue Sky, Pheonix: 1901
 Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Indie Rock</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist: Midnight Riot </title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-04-20-music-playlist-midnight-riot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-04-20-music-playlist-midnight-riot/</guid>
      <description>Poppy, punky, alternative sounds you&#39;re probably already familiar with through their advertising business. They&#39;re not so far on Wiki yet, but below are descriptions from their webpage.&#34;Midnight Riot is the edgy duo brought to life by soulful rocker Emily Kopp, and guitarist/producer Justin Beckler. Drawing from their love of pop and old school indie rock, their creations feature good old-fashioned guitar riffs, room-shaking stomps and claps, and hooks that sink so deep you&#39;ll be humming them for weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist Feature - Le Tigre</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-10-playlist-le-tigre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-10-playlist-le-tigre/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Le Tigre - Bang! Bang!, Mediocrity Rules, Phanta, My My Metrocard, Deceptacon, Hot Topic, Sweetie, What&amp;#39;s Yr Take On Cassavetes, Friendship Station, After Dark, FYI, Gone B4 Yr Home, Keep On Living
 Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Le TigreThe &#34;Le Tigre&#34; sound is uniquely cacophonous, punky, and at the same time invigoratingly rebellious. It&#39;s also distinctfrom their usurp-tuous message, which is somewhat synonymous with that of those rebellious femmes &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Music You Can Work To</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-02-hello-music-playlist-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-02-hello-music-playlist-work/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Audionautix: Fat Caps, Roboskater, Opus One, Cycles, Yeah Yeah, Ice Cold, Ooh Hey, Sunday Spirit, Radio Rock, Macaroon 5, Pop Star, Get A Move On, Sk8tboard, Tech Talk, Vanishing Horizon, Lightning Bugs, Code Blue, Rubix Cube, Carlo Virz: Tommaso Groove, John Deley: Bumber Tag, Silent Partner: Weekend In The City, Spaz Cardigan: Rinse and Repeat,  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Free Beats, Loops, and CutsNotesThere&#39;s a lot of good music made for television streams these days.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
