<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning Center on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/learning-center/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning Center on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/learning-center/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Highlighting Packages</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-27-emacs-highlighting-packages/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-27-emacs-highlighting-packages/</guid>
      <description>This post covers &#34;Highlights&#34; from the appearance section of my init.   Appearance  Entering and Exiting Emacs Default Appearance Customizations Themes Highlights Hydras Appearance Hydra    Preamble Emacs is old school. You&#39;re either new to it - which means you wouldn&#39;t be here unless it was your type of thing - or you know what you&#39;re looking for. In either case, go to the side bar of this page and click on the &#39;Emacs&#39; tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Hydra Config and an Appearance Hydra</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-27-emacs-hydra-set-up-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-27-emacs-hydra-set-up-code/</guid>
      <description>This post covers &#34;Highlights&#34; from the appearance section of my init.   Appearance  Entering and Exiting Emacs Default Appearance Customizations Themes Highlights Hydras Appearance Hydra    Preamble Emacs is old school. You&#39;re either new to it - which means you wouldn&#39;t be here unless it was your type of thing - or you know what you&#39;re looking for. In either case, go to the side bar of this page and click on the &#39;Emacs&#39; tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Cognitive Ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-25-developing-cognitive-ambidexterity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-25-developing-cognitive-ambidexterity/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s motivational video is about the benefits of cognitive ambidexterity, why you should take some time to work on that each week, and how you can do that.
   
For those of you that come here for my emacs posts, don&#39;t worry, nothing has changed. I have been working on multidisciplinary studies for over twenty years. I routinely work at several types of activities. These include psychology work, finance, data science, computer programming, writing, and now also vlogging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Themes and All-The-Icons</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-22-emacs-themes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-22-emacs-themes/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s post covers &#34;Themes&#34; from the appearance section of my init.   Appearance  Entering and Exiting Emacs Default Appearance Customizations Themes Highlights Hydras Appearance Hydra    Preamble Emacs is old school. You&#39;re either new to it - which means you wouldn&#39;t be here unless it was your type of thing - or you know what you&#39;re looking for. In either case, go to the side bar of this page and click on the &#39;Emacs&#39; tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Appearance, Entering and Exiting (&#43; Some Functions)</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-20-emacs-enter-exit-appearance/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-20-emacs-enter-exit-appearance/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s post covers &#34;Entering and Exiting Emacs&#34; and &#34;Default Appearance Customizations&#34; from the appearance section of my init.   Appearance  Entering and Exiting Emacs Default Appearance Customizations Themes Highlights Hydras Appearance Hydra    Preamble Emacs is old school. You&#39;re either new to it - which means you wouldn&#39;t be here unless it was your type of thing - or you know what you&#39;re looking for. In either case, go to the side bar of this page and click on the &#39;Emacs&#39; tag.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Configuration Posframe and Which Key, Some Key Bindings</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-17-emacs-posframe-which-key/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-17-emacs-posframe-which-key/</guid>
      <description>Emacs is old school. You&#39;re either new to it - which means you wouldn&#39;t be here unless it was your type of thing - or you know what you&#39;re looking for. In either case, go to the side bar of this page and click on the &#39;Emacs&#39; tag. Then read the posts from oldest to newest.
In this earlier emacs post I covered lines 534 - 656 of my configuration file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Emacs Shell Hydra</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-15-emacs-shell-hydra/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-15-emacs-shell-hydra/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s post jumps ahead to the shell hydra  Emacs is old school. You&#39;re either new to it - which means you wouldn&#39;t be here unless it was your type of thing - or you know what you&#39;re looking for. In either case, go to the side bar of this page and click on the &#39;Emacs&#39; tag. Then read the posts from oldest to newest.
In the last emacs post I covered lines 534 - 656 of my configuration file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith, Keynes, and Penrose</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-15-smith-keynes-and-penrose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-15-smith-keynes-and-penrose/</guid>
      <description>What do Adam Smith, John Maynard Keynes, and Roger Penrose have in common? Well, certainly there must have been something, but it wasn&#39;t the content of their books. Smith and Keynes were economists, Penrose is a mathematical physicist. Still, I&#39;ve mentioned them here together because in a way I&#39;m telling a story and Roger Penrose&#39;s book is to me right now in some ways what Keynes&#39;s book once was. Let&#39;s start with me and Adam Smith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Frames, Buffers, Lines, Defaults (&#43; Some Functions)</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-11-emacs-frames-buffers-defaults-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-11-emacs-frames-buffers-defaults-functions/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s post has some of the default settings from my initialization file.   SET UP, DEFAULTS, AND CUSTOMIZATION  Necessary Adjustments when you set-up on a new computer Paths to Update on Change Executable Paths Libraries Function declarations Emacs Customization Seperate File Emax Defaults Some Defaults Frames, Buffers, And Lines Some Custom Default Functions Some New Key Bindings Popup, Pos-tip,Tooltip, Posframe Which Key   
Preamble Emacs is old school.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Defaults</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-09-some-emacs-defaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-02-09-some-emacs-defaults/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s post has some of the default settings from my initialization file.   SET UP, DEFAULTS, AND CUSTOMIZATION  Necessary Adjustments when you set-up on a new computer Paths to Update on Change Executable Paths Libraries Function declarations Emacs Customization Seperate File Emax Defaults Some Defaults Frames, Buffers, And Lines Some Custom Default Functions Some New Key Bindings Popup, Pos-tip,Tooltip, Posframe Which Key   
Preamble Last post I covered function declarations from the above subsection, lines 135 - 424 of my configuration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Business the Ultimate Resource</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-04-business-the-ultimate-resource/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-04-business-the-ultimate-resource/</guid>
      <description>This is a fantastic book. I bought it when it was first published (in 2002), and my copy is well used. The idea seems to be basically to publish everything you need to know about business, that a book can teach you, between two covers. The reality of course is that there are a lot of books on business, and many of them are inspiring and educational. Moreover, books like this one are great for people who want to understand key processes in big business, and even helpful for those who want to build better small business, but, despite what Chekhov said about it, business is not about processes, buzz words, or other people&#39;s money, it&#39;s about value exchange.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Functions (And Program Launcher Hydra)</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-01-31-some-emacs-configuration-functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-01-31-some-emacs-configuration-functions/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s post has some functions from the functions declaration section of the beginning of my initialization file.  SET UP, DEFAULTS, AND CUSTOMIZATION  Necessary Adjustments when you set-up on a new computer Paths to Update on Change Executable Paths Libraries Function declarations Emacs Customization Seperate File Emax Defaults Some Defaults Frames, Buffers, And Lines Some Custom Default Functions Some New Key Bindings Popup, Pos-tip,Tooltip, Posframe Which Key</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Alignment Through Communication</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-01-30-achieving-alignment-through-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-01-30-achieving-alignment-through-communication/</guid>
      <description>Psychologists do important work, but it doesn&#39;t take one to know that people operate a lot like computers. We&#39;ve got code inside that issues a response when stimulated. The more you know the person, the more you know what responses to expect. In any organization team building improves organizational outcomes. But what is going on when team members bond?
Alignment is a concept that explains what&#39;s going on. Let each line in this chart represent a person; but more than that, let it represent their psychology, the millions of associations their mind contains between images and expectations, words and definitions, and information and responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Installation and Defaults</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-01-24-emacs-installation-and-defaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-01-24-emacs-installation-and-defaults/</guid>
      <description>Directly below are the subheadings to the first main heading of my initialization file, see my last post Emacs Configuration Overview. I&#39;ll go through the lines of code in order, but remember, the line numbers you see in Hugo&#39;s code block css styling are relative to the code on this page not the emacs initialization file [Hugo is the Static Content Management System based on GO I used to make this blog].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Configuration Overview</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-01-19-emacs-configuration-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-01-19-emacs-configuration-overview/</guid>
      <description>Below are some notes covering among other things why I got into Emacs, where I got my version, and how my configuration is organized. As mentioned before, other text editors in use today, like Atom, IntelliJ Idea, or Sublime Text are awesome, and offer also great selections of unique packages. Atom, for example, has some super useful snippet packages. You can convert them into Yasnippet format (an Emacs snippet package), but it&#39;s a hassle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Program Launcher</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2019-09-23-windows-program-launcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2019-09-23-windows-program-launcher/</guid>
      <description>For any readers setting up configuration files for their emacs editor, here is the quick and easy code for the windows program launcher shown in the image below.    Here&amp;rsquo;s the config code: 
1 2 3 4 5 6 7  ;path of program you want in your launcher (defvar name-of-program-p &amp;#34;C:/full-path-to-program/program.exe&amp;#34;) ; launcher function (defun launch-program-name () (interactive) (w32-shell-execute nil name-of-program-p nil) );end launch-program-name    Then you can put the launch function name in your hydra config, like this:  (&amp;quot;p&amp;quot; launch-program-name &amp;quot;Launch This Program&amp;quot;)  For the generate hydra code see this post: Emacs Bookmarks  Thanks for reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2019-10-20-emacs-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2019-10-20-emacs-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Jumping To Directories In Emacs If you want to accomplish things efficiently with your computer, you will benefit from mastering a text editor. I use emacs as a general project manager for web development, writing, and organizing thoughts, materials, and actions. Jumping to and from directories and files enables quickly me to get things done more efficiently. To do this I use a few different packages and functions. They are:  Bookmarks</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Moves Habits Tell You Where</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-15-life-moves-habits-tell-you-where/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-15-life-moves-habits-tell-you-where/</guid>
      <description>Habits can be bad, like when they deter progress toward your current set of goals, and they can be good, like when they move you closer to your goals or align you with them (if, for example, your goal is to attain a certain state of being). Habits include things like the way you spend your time, the way you think about things, and the way you communicate. They determine where you are going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs With an Interface</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2019-09-08-emacs-with-an-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2019-09-08-emacs-with-an-interface/</guid>
      <description>What&#39;s All This About Text Editors? I always used to ask, why do people post about their text-editors? These days I know the reason. Computers are lightening fast, using them isn&#39;t. You need to leave what you are doing to turn on another piece of software. You have to search for files. You&#39;re constantly having to remember how a process works, or search around the IDE to figure out how to do something again.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bean Machine</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-07-the-bean-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-07-the-bean-machine/</guid>
      <description>Staying Focused On Being Yourself Here is something to think about. What does it mean to be normal?
The picture below is a picture of a bean machine,  also known as a Quincunx,  a Dalton Board,  or Plinko. 
What happens to the ball when it gets dropped into the top of the bean machine? It gets bounced around right? Does the ball get to choose in which slot it will end up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Harry Met Sally</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-23-time-value-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-23-time-value-of-money/</guid>
      <description>What is the Best Age To Invest? According to value investors, like Warren Buffet, the secret sauce of finance can be explained in five simple words:
Investing is all about timing. The five simple words that contain the secret to investing like a billionaire are: The time value of money. While money doesn&#39;t exactly grow on trees, it does actually grow like a tree-a big, green, Christmasy [acceptable?], money tree. Yes, most people eventually learn the sheer power of savings and compound interest, but few people learn it early enough to use it wisely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is An ETF?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-18-what-is-an-etf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-18-what-is-an-etf/</guid>
      <description>What is an ETF? Electronically traded funds are close-end funds that trade on a stock exchange. They are managed through a creation and redemption scheme that ties their contents to those of an index, or selection of investments that meet specific criteria. The value of an ETF is determined by market forces. When the value deviates from the net asset value (NAV) of the underlying investments, traders trade on the arbitrage opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working With Data In R</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2017-05-29-getting-data-into-r/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2017-05-29-getting-data-into-r/</guid>
      <description>Video Tutorial. Loading data into R via Emacs Speaks Statistics, and doing some operations on it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-11-12-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-11-12-principles/</guid>
      <description>It is honorable to respect all peoples, given they are not acting outside the social contract, nor seeking to usurp unjustly another&#39;s rights or freedoms.
The law protects people in societies and enables societies to function. To the extent it remains to do so, it should be upheld at every turn. When there are laws that do not serve all citizens in a society equally, those laws should be challenged and amended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Overview Of The Emacs Text Editor</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-08-02-an-emacs-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Aug 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-08-02-an-emacs-overview/</guid>
      <description>Video Tutorial. Emacs Overview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Psychology</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Numerous studies have examined what intangible and tangible factors might cause one organization to outperform others over a period of time. There is no question that ideas and talent are invaluable, but it is no longer any surprise that the single most important factor affecting organizational performance is organizational psychology. Here are a few examples:
Ray Dalio runs Bridgewater Associates, one of the largest hedge funds in the world. In Connecticut, he&#39;s got 1500 people, some of whom are the best and brightest brains in the financial sector, but does Ray cite his PhDs, research acumen, and process as his number one a comparative advantage?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Psychology -</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology-m/</guid>
      <description>Numerous studies have examined what intangible and tangible factors might cause one organization to outperform others over a period of time. There is no question that ideas and talent are invaluable, but it is no longer any surprise that the single most important factor affecting organizational performance is organizational psychology. Here are a few examples:
Ray Dalio runs Bridgewater Associates, one of the largest hedge funds in the world. In Connecticut, he&#39;s got 1500 people, some of whom are the best and brightest brains in the financial sector, but does Ray cite his PhDs, research acumen, and process as his number one a comparative advantage?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science And The Law</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-08-data-science-and-the-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-08-data-science-and-the-law/</guid>
      <description>Information technologies and the data they create are changing the world rapidly in a multitude of ways. The legal profession, one of the most traditional and adverse to change, is beginning to adapt. A new breed of data savvy lawyers are entering legal circles everywhere and bringing with them an inertia from new technologies.
Firstly, the legal profession stands to gain from those data driven insights that are common across organizations, like more accurately targeted marketing, more informed case selection, more efficient internal procedures, and pricing models that minimize both losses of producer surplus, and dead-weight losses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Economic Policy</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-30-what-is-economic-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-30-what-is-economic-policy/</guid>
      <description>What is economic policy? If economics can be described as the study of the allocation of scarce resources among agents, economic policy can be described as the public rules and regulations that guide that allocation. Wherever a society is governed with laws, there will be laws that influence the economic prosperity of constituents, producers, and suppliers, as well as the distribution of resources among agents within the economy. Those rules constitute economic policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Maths Programming</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-25-what-is-maths-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-25-what-is-maths-programming/</guid>
      <description>What is maths programming? Mathematical programming, or computational programming, is the process of translating mathematically representable problems into computer languages then harnessing the power of computers to solve them. Along with the Internet, and task facilitation, mathematical programming is probably the most important contribution from the modern computer to human evolution. There are many kinds of mathematical programming techniques. Among these are: linear and non-linear programming, integer programming, mixed complementary problems, networks, goal programming, multiple objective optimization, queuing theory, regression analysis, and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Decision Analysis</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-23-what-is-decision-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-23-what-is-decision-analysis/</guid>
      <description>What is decision analysis? Decision analysis is a subcategory of decision science. Ultimately, all data science could be classified as decision science, because the entire point of data analytics and informatics is to enable better decision making processes to yield better outcomes from decisions. While decision science and decision analysis cannot eliminate the possibility of sub-optimal outcomes, they are in themselves useful if not mandatory processes. They can, for example, enable teams or decision makers to move forward with confidence in their assessments of decision variable behaviour across decision parameters, and thus with more reasonable expectation of probable outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Optimization</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-21-what-is-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-21-what-is-optimization/</guid>
      <description>What is optimization Optimization is about making choices that lead to first best outcomes. Mathematically, optimization is usually described with differential calculus, though when functions are linear, and problems are adequately fit substitution can lead to optimal solutions. In mathematics, optimization first requires the delineation of an objective function, a dependent function meant to be maximized or minimized through variations in the independent functions that predict it. Solving optimization problems therefore requires identifying maximum or minimum points on the objective function and qualifying those points as local or global maximums or minimums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Macroeconomics</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-19-what-are-macroeconomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-19-what-are-macroeconomics/</guid>
      <description>What is macroeconomics Macroeconomics is the field of economics that deals with aggregated quantities. Microeconomics, for example, might deal with firm level economics, while macroeconomics might deal with aggregate firms level economics, the economics of all the firms in an economy together. Macroeconomics therefore includes the study of national level and supranational level economics.
What kind of indicators are macroeconomic? Macroeconomic indicators include trade indicators, like the trade balance, and trade openness, but also indicators that describe other facets of the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is International Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-01-18-what-is-internation-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-01-18-what-is-internation-trade/</guid>
      <description>What is international trade? International trade is the movement of goods across national borders. Because bilateral exchange rates change frequently, international trade is watched closely by national and supranational governments. Small changes in currency pair spreads can impact the movement of goods across borders and, as a consequence, the health of a nation&#39;s domestic industry and its employment levels.
How do organizations measure international trade? Physical goods (commodity trade) are tracked by governments when they enter various economic and trade zones within an economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Modelling</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-14-what-is-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-14-what-is-modelling/</guid>
      <description>What is modelling? Modelling is an important part of decision science. Modellers make simplified representations of reality to produce judgements about reality and guide real decisions. Models can be abstract and theoretical, or data driven and empirical. Both categories can be prescriptive, predictive, or descriptive.
Why model? Modelling is a cost-effective way to test the successes and failures of potential projects without committing large-scale resources. Modelling is also useful as means of building support necessary to successfully launch projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are Statistics</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-11-what-are-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-11-what-are-statistics/</guid>
      <description>What are statistics? Statistics are transformations of data through calculation. While in theory any calculation done with data yields a statistic, in practice statistics are associated with scientific and field specific calculations. For example, during preparation phase your data is frequently explored and analysed using simple plotting techniques that present meaningful descriptive statistics from the data or data subset, like the mean, median, and/or quartile ranges. As another example, in macroeconomics, various calculations with data yield well known statistics like GDP, inflation, or trade balance by sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Data Wrangling</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-08-what-is-data-wrangling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-08-what-is-data-wrangling/</guid>
      <description>What is data wrangling? Data wrangling is the process of preparing data for analysis or computation. It includes transforming data into various formats and statistical derivations, cleaning data to account for missing observations, clumsy data types, or outright errors, and arranging data into workable categorized data sets.
When should data be cleaned? Anyone working with data knows it needs to be cleaned many times along the data pipeline. After data is collected, it must be wrangled before it is stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Data Science</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-03-what-is-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-03-what-is-data-science/</guid>
      <description>What is data science? The science of data promises to change the world, but many of us do not know what data science is. This segement gives you our answer.
Data science is the science of data analytics in the context of scientific query. The data scientist first asks scientific questions, then gathers data relevant to those questions, and finally applies a variety of computer processes and statistical and probabilistic theories to derive answers to those questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>