<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>opinion on Cloud Nine</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/opinion/</link><description>Recent content in opinion on Cloud Nine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/opinion/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Why The Julian Assange Trial is Important to You</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-03-17-relevence-of-julian-assange/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-03-17-relevence-of-julian-assange/</guid><description>Forgive me for pointing
out the obvious, which you surely already know, but I see no harm in expanding on the Assange trial and hope you will at least thank me for not posting
yet another picture of toilet paper.
First, note the image to the right says "Journalism is not a Crime." It does not say "Do not extradite Julian Assange." I'd
like more information, but I'm not in a position to pick sides.</description></item><item><title>Where Is The Money?</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-12-03-where-is-the-money/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-12-03-where-is-the-money/</guid><description>As Krugman might say, "...it's in the market, stupid." The most influential economy in the world is poised to raise
interest rates, but not because of inflation. Central banks in major parts of the world are still at the zero bound, and core prices are
behaving as they should when targeted only because liquidity is trapped on balance sheets as inventory. What happened? Why did monetary
easing take half a decade to jump-start the US dollar economy?</description></item><item><title>BIS Warns of Low Rates</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</guid><description>The Bank of International Settlements (BIS) continues to reprimand contemporary central banking culture for easy money
fixes it argues feed instability by creating global economic conditions that foster bubbles. As the story goes, demand side policies are
band-aids slapped on top of deep structural wounds. This is especially the case in a world where financial intermediation dominates money
channels with a vast array of levers, ropes, and pulleys that push the lag between easing and higher demand more and more unmeasurably into
the future.</description></item><item><title>To Raise or Not to Raise</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-02-26-to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</link><pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-02-26-to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</guid><description>US indicators out this week, like the Chicago PMI and the CPI estimates, support both sides of a US turn-around, the output side and the
consumption side. Yet still the FED, though widely expected to raise rates in the summer, remains tight-lipped about it, downplaying
positive economic indicators. This sounds like policy speak for 'we want to keep the option in our pocket,' and there is good reason. While the UK and the US have been running the money tap seemingly forever, at least since 1929 part-two, the great depression strikes back,
the rest of the known world, and the unknown world, is starting to catch up.</description></item><item><title>Upcoming ECB Rate Changes</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2014-06-04-upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2014-06-04-upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</guid><description>Yesterday's flash Harmonized Consumer Price Index indicated a drop in EMU price rises to 0.5%. Given the ECB's primary target is price
stability, markets are widely anticipating tomorrow's ECB meeting will see overnight interest rates reduced to negative levels.This would
have banks less likely to deposit daily surpluses in the ECB overnight and more likely to loan them out. They would also commit a smaller
portion of liquidity to paying down liabilities previously acquired with the ECB.</description></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Outlook</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-08-14-macroeconomic-outlook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-08-14-macroeconomic-outlook/</guid><description>Introduction
The following article comprises my general world economic outlook. It is necessary to clarify a few points for the
reader. Firstly, the exercise is positive rather than normative. For example, any mention of oil should be read as an inchoate view of where
world oil prices, or supply and demand, may go in future periods, rather than a statement that policies should pursue increased oil output,
or that carbon fuel consumption is net surplus enhancing.</description></item><item><title>Strong Dollar Could Be Good For Canada</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-11-28-strong-dollar-could-be-good-for-canada/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-11-28-strong-dollar-could-be-good-for-canada/</guid><description>Pundits
of the double-dip recession theory cite the now globally anticipated fallout of the U.S. dollar as a key source. The fed is printing money
like confetti, they say. The U.S. Treasury bill bubble is soon to pop, they add. The newly coined (U.S. dollar-carry trade) (it used
to be the yen-carry trade) is driving commodities through the roof, they squeal. The concerns are many. For example, rampant increases in
U.</description></item><item><title>Bill That Sank Ignatieff Looks Likely to Float</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-11-09-bill-sank-ignatieff-likely-to-float/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-11-09-bill-sank-ignatieff-likely-to-float/</guid><description>Remember last October? Under Stephane Dion, the Liberals were, by no small margin, consistently behind the Conservatives
in the national public opinion polls. Then the Conservatives released their economic update and political mayhem ensued. Stephane, Jack and
Gille went up the hill and planned a coalition coupe. Stephan Harper set a frighteningly partisan political precedent by proroguing
parliament when the conservatives were facing an election they looked likely to lose. And, after Mr.</description></item><item><title>Dealing With The HST</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-09-15-dealing-with-the-hst/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-09-15-dealing-with-the-hst/</guid><description>Protests across the province last month made it clear to British Columbians that the PST/GST harmonization announced on July 23 by Premier
Gordon Campbell is not going over well. Former Premier Bill Vander Zalm grasped onto the issue like a life raft, presumably hoping to
resurrect his long-thought dead but apparently still alive Social Credit initiatives. The NDP are joining Mr. Vander Zalm in the attack on
the provincial Liberal for, perhaps, partisan reasons (it's worth nothing that New Democrats in prairies support the HST).</description></item><item><title>Bringing Down The House</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-12-04-bringing-down-the-house/</link><pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-12-04-bringing-down-the-house/</guid><description>What ever happened to Canadian government for all Canadians? Clearly out the window. Whatever happened to non-partisan
politics? Has there ever been such a thing? Do we really need an economic stimulus package, or is the recent uproar in the House of Commons
little more than partisan on partisan? Will a coalition government serve the people well? Is democracy being put to the test?
Well, it's not much, but technically an increase in newspaper sales should cause an increase in GDP, and if one opens
the paper it's hard not to imagine an increase in newspaper sales.</description></item><item><title>Wedding Bell, Business And State Tie The knot.</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-11-30-wedding-bells-business-and-state-tie-the-knot/</link><pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-11-30-wedding-bells-business-and-state-tie-the-knot/</guid><description>Last month, before U.S. election results, I was chatting with a friend about economic political history. He wrote a line
that stuck with me. He wrote (Western civilization has got to stop patting itself on the back for separating church and state and get on
with the business of separating business and state.) At the time I thought the line might one day just come off (I was thinking of
receding lobbyist influence given the likelihood of a democrat government.</description></item><item><title>The Great Debate Revisited</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-11-13-the-great-debate-revisited/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-11-13-the-great-debate-revisited/</guid><description>Okay, Obama is in the news, he's made friends, he's made headlines, he's made history-he's everywhere. The world stands in awe. Democracy
has been authenticated. It's no longer a form of government that claims to champion the cause of the marginalized while craftily concealing
the domination of the under-privileged by autocrats and oligarchs---it's the real the thing: true government by popular representation.
And it's clear that people view Obama as a human being--- someone with a conscience, who believes that America stands for democracy,
liberty, freedom, and the rule of law.</description></item><item><title>More Tories At The Table, More Water In The Liberal Hull</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-26-more-tories-at-the-table-more-water-in-the-liberal-hull/</link><pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-26-more-tories-at-the-table-more-water-in-the-liberal-hull/</guid><description>Was it Warren Buffet who reminded us of the irrationality in the stock market? What was it he said, stock markets are
people driven and people are irrational? I'd like to add the movements of populist governments to his irrational people bit as, it seems
to me, both populist governments and stock markets are guided by public opinion. If public opinion is an expression of human behavior, (run
that one by your local shrink if you like,) does that make it the result of feelings, instincts, and herd-like responses to media induced
perceptions (not a herd of hippo's mind you, that's the U.</description></item><item><title>Stimulating Interest</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-24-stimulating-interest/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-24-stimulating-interest/</guid><description>So world leaders (note: 20 of them) have agreed to come together in a first ever meeting of the G20 to discuss a
restructuring of global financial market systems. Finally, economic and politically minded people everywhere are revisiting the decisions
that have shaped our global economy into the fertile soil for crisis that it has become.
Milton Friedman's legacy is under attack. The concepts of nationalism and socialism in the state are not only being
reconsidered, they are being re-instituted as we speak (the nationalization of big banks globally).</description></item><item><title>Wallstreet's Liquidity Problem</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-22-wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-22-wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</guid><description>It doesn't take a rocket scientist to see that addressing the liquidity problem on Wall Street by borrowing to restore
the ability to lend does not address the underlying aggregate debt issue.
The common sense approach says that to avoid a sudden crash or some kind of long drawn out debt deflation, the American
Government needs to address the ability of the real economy to earn, borrow and spend. And in this sense yes, much of the relief could have
gone to debtors at large and not the creditors, who to pay their new debts will have to lend more.</description></item></channel></rss>