<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/current/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>The Uncelebrated Whimsy of Princeton&#39;s Own Lexical Database, Wordnet</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-04-11-wordnet-princetons-lexical-database/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-04-11-wordnet-princetons-lexical-database/</guid>
      <description>If you use Wordnet as an extension to your text editor, you may eventually begin to wonder what is up with all the nutsy downward sloping oddly indented syntax. Then you might go here, to wikipedia, and read up on all the madness. Or you can browse a few of the tidbits we&#39;ve pasted below. This Summary is From Wordnet&#39;s WebsiteWordNet superficially resembles a thesaurus, in that it groups words together based on their meanings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Swing of Change</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-09-06-vimeo-jazz-vid-editors-choice/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-09-06-vimeo-jazz-vid-editors-choice/</guid>
      <description> </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Tokyo Megaplex </title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-07-26-music-playlist-tokyo-megaplex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-07-26-music-playlist-tokyo-megaplex/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Tokyo Megaplex - Pinapple House Party, The Hole Foods Experience, Ahhhhh, The Price Is Wrong  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Tokyo MegaplexAs I understand, Tokyo Megaplex is a Brooklyn musical artist. I listened to a few of their tracks and enjoyed these ones.If you can listen beyond the Hip Hop (a decidedly specific segment of the musical spectrum), they could go nicely with augmented reality. Augmented Reality is a concept developed in recent years by designer KEIICHIMATSUDA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What&#39;s So Great About the Cloverfield Paradox?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-04-10-cloverfield-paradox-film/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-04-10-cloverfield-paradox-film/</guid>
      <description>Nothing, but it could have been worse. Actually, I got bored anddidn&#39;t watch it all. I&#39;m writing about it here because there were a couple of things I liked. I&#39;ll tell you about those shortly.
First, disclaimer: I didn&#39;t watch any of the Cloverfield series. They must have been good though, because they made a lot of money. The box office from the first one, &#34;Cloverfield,&#34; released in 2008, something like tripled cost.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why The Julian Assange Trial is Important to You</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-03-17-relevence-of-julian-assange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-03-17-relevence-of-julian-assange/</guid>
      <description>Forgive me for pointingout the obvious, which you surely already know, but I see no harm in expanding on the Assange trial and hope you will at least thank me for not postingyet another picture of toilet paper.
First, note the image to the right says &#34;Journalism is not a Crime.&#34; It does not say &#34;Do not extradite Julian Assange.&#34; I&#39;dlike more information, but I&#39;m not in a position to pick sides.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
