<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>music on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/music/</link>
    <description>Recent content in music on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/music/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Marin Marais</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-31-music-playlist-classical-moments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-31-music-playlist-classical-moments/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Marin Marais: Suite in A Minor. Book 3 (Gavotte),Sarabande A L&amp;#39;Espagnol,Chaconne En Rondeau. Book 2, Prelude En Harpegement. Book 5, Tombeau Pour Marais Le Cadet. Book 5, Suite In B Minor. Tombeau Pour Monsieur De Lully, Marche Persane Dite La Savigny. Book 5, Le Labyrinthe. Book 4, Le Tableau Doperation De La Taille. Book 5, Suite In G Minor (Suite En Sol Mineur) : Prelude, Le Tourbillon. Book 4, Works for Viola da Gamba (XVII th century)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - A Wednesday Evening Alternative Playlist</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-21-music-playlist-wednesday-mix/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-21-music-playlist-wednesday-mix/</guid>
      <description> Songs: Hello Oasis: She&amp;#39;s Electric, Little Scream: Love As A Weapon, Kevin Morby: Dorothy, Rat Head: Abbrasive, RJD2: Ghostwriter, Caravan Palace: Dramaphone, Monatik: What is Crazy About, Little Big and Tatarka: Arriba
  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Wednesday Mix   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Some Music From The Band Weezer</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-21-music-playlist-weezer-weezer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-10-21-music-playlist-weezer-weezer/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Back To The Shack, Undone: Sweater Song, Say it Ain&amp;#39;t So, Hash Pipe, Hero, Go Away, My Name Is Jonas, The End of The Game, The Good Life, Beverly Hills, We Are All Drugs, Pork And Beans, Perfect Situation, King of the World, I Want You To, Buddy Holly   Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Weezer   Formation and first years (1989-1994) &#34;Vocalist and guitarist Rivers Cuomo moved to Los Angeles in 1989 with his high school metal band, Avant Garde, later renamed Zoom.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Lithuanian Music, Indie Rock</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-08-01-music-playlist-lithuanian-indie-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-08-01-music-playlist-lithuanian-indie-music/</guid>
      <description> Songs: No Real Pioneers - at Ymir Audio, Verslo rizikos rezervas - Mano vaikas prazilo, Verslo Rizikos Rezervas - Kur plauki?, Biplan - Labas rytas, Daddy Was A Milkman - Seasons, Empti Radio laga, Donny Montell feat. Mark Les - LEISK MYLET, FREAKS ON FLOOR: Star,Rasabasa: Interstellar, KaYra: Alligator   Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Lithuanian Music   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Indie Rock, Featuring Spoon</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-07-30-music-playlist-indie-rock-spoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-07-30-music-playlist-indie-rock-spoon/</guid>
      <description> Songs: Spoon - Finer Feelings, Foster The People - Pick U Up, Datarock- Fa Fa Fa, The Zolas - Molotov Girls, the ponys - double vision, Vampire Weekend - A-Punk, Modest Mouse - Dashboard, Vampire Weekend - Cousins , Arcade Fire - No Cars Go, Belle and Sebastian - Legal Man, Vampire Weekend: A Punk, Electric Light Orchestra: Mr. Blue Sky, Pheonix: 1901
  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Indie Rock   </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Jazz, Featuring Cannonball Adderly</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-07-29-music-playlist-jazz-cannonball-adderly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-07-29-music-playlist-jazz-cannonball-adderly/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Cannonball Adderly: Autumn Leaves, Wabash, Toy, Groovy Samba, Oscar Peterson: Take the A train, The Girl from Ipanima, Sometimes Im Happy, Happy Go Lucky Localaka: Night Train, A Little Jazz Exercise, Charlie Parker: Bloomdido, Dizzy Gillespie: One Note Samba, Con Alma, Beale Street, Flute Blues
  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Jazz 2  Julian Edwin &#34;Cannonball&#34; Adderley (September 15, 1928 - August 8, 1975) was an American jazz alto saxophonist of the hard bop era of the 1950s and 1960s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Tokyo Megaplex </title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-07-26-music-playlist-tokyo-megaplex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-07-26-music-playlist-tokyo-megaplex/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Tokyo Megaplex - Pinapple House Party, The Hole Foods Experience, Ahhhhh, The Price Is Wrong   Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Tokyo Megaplex  As I understand, Tokyo Megaplex is a Brooklyn musical artist. I listened to a few of their tracks and enjoyed these ones. If you can listen beyond the Hip Hop (a decidedly specific segment of the musical spectrum), they could go nicely with augmented reality. Augmented Reality is a concept developed in recent years by designer KEIICHI MATSUDA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist: Classical</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-06-28-music-playlist-classical/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-06-28-music-playlist-classical/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Sheku-Kanneh-Mason -Song of the Birds,Klengel Hymnus, Op. 57, Vanessa Mae: Pagaini: La Campanella, Victor Lyadov: Danza ritual del Fuego, Bond - Quixote, Kaori Fujii: Allemande BWV 1013 - J.S. Bach, Hilary Hahn - J.S. Bach: Partita for Violin Solo No. 1 in B Minor, Partita No. 3 prelude, Yo-Yo Ma - Bach: Cello Suite No. 3 in C Major, Casals - Song of The Birds - Camille Thomas, Sibelius : Violin Concerto (Hilary Hahn), Hilary Hahn - Tchaikovsky - Violin Concerto in D Major, Op.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist: Midnight Riot </title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-04-20-music-playlist-midnight-riot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-04-20-music-playlist-midnight-riot/</guid>
      <description>Poppy, punky, alternative sounds you&#39;re probably already familiar with through their advertising business. They&#39;re not so far on Wiki yet, but below are descriptions from their webpage.      &#34;Midnight Riot is the edgy duo brought to life by soulful rocker Emily Kopp, and guitarist/producer Justin Beckler. Drawing from their love of pop and old school indie rock, their creations feature good old-fashioned guitar riffs, room-shaking stomps and claps, and hooks that sink so deep you&#39;ll be humming them for weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist Feature - Le Tigre</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-10-playlist-le-tigre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-10-playlist-le-tigre/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Le Tigre - Bang! Bang!, Mediocrity Rules, Phanta, My My Metrocard, Deceptacon, Hot Topic, Sweetie, What&amp;#39;s Yr Take On Cassavetes, Friendship Station, After Dark, FYI, Gone B4 Yr Home, Keep On Living
  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Le Tigre  The &#34;Le Tigre&#34; sound is uniquely cacophonous, punky, and at the same time invigoratingly rebellious. It&#39;s also distinct from their usurp-tuous message, which is somewhat synonymous with that of those rebellious femmes &#34;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Music You Can Work To</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-02-hello-music-playlist-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-02-hello-music-playlist-work/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Audionautix: Fat Caps, Roboskater, Opus One, Cycles, Yeah Yeah, Ice Cold, Ooh Hey, Sunday Spirit, Radio Rock, Macaroon 5, Pop Star, Get A Move On, Sk8tboard, Tech Talk, Vanishing Horizon, Lightning Bugs, Code Blue, Rubix Cube, Carlo Virz: Tommaso Groove, John Deley: Bumber Tag, Silent Partner: Weekend In The City, Spaz Cardigan: Rinse and Repeat,   Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Free Beats, Loops, and Cuts  Notes There&#39;s a lot of good music made for television streams these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist: Exercise Bike</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-01-hello-music-playlist-exercise-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-01-hello-music-playlist-exercise-bike/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Juanitos: Sai-k-delic Party, Mark Grant: Jazzy Kinda Sum&amp;#39;n, Dr. Kucho! &amp;amp; Gregor Salto: Can&amp;#39;t Stop Playing (Oliver Heldens &amp;amp; Gregor Salto Remix), FISHER: Losing It, Dom Dolla: Take It (Sonny Fodera Remix), David Bendeth: Feel The Real (Jazz &amp;#39;n&amp;#39; Groove Ultra Classic Mix), Big Sexy: Another World (Passport Remix), Paul Johnson: Get Get Down, Armand Van Helden: You Don&amp;#39;t Know Me, Claptone: Cream, Bow Wow Wow: I Want Candy, Todd Terje: Inspector Norse, Ida Corr vs Fedde Le Grand: Let Me Think About It, Alex Gaudino, Featuring Shena: Watch Out, Crystal Waters: 100% Pure Love, Johnny Corporate: Sunday Shoutin&amp;#39; [Original Mix], Trueby Trio: Make A Move (Spiller Remix), Noze: Remember Love, You Man &amp;amp; Jerge: Everybody, Koop: Relaxin at Club F****n (Dorfmeister vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Andy Cooper Hip Hop</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-11-02-music-playlist-andy-cooper/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-11-02-music-playlist-andy-cooper/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Andy Cooper: Here Comes Another One - Featuring Blabbermouf, Can&amp;#39;t Be Satisfied, Oohs and Ahs, Let The Tiger Out, Have A Good Time, Get On That - Featuring DJ Format, Don&amp;#39;t Hold The Feeling You, Last of a Dying Breed, Chasing The Funk, Blind Faith, Bring It To Me, Room To Breath, Intensify
  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Andy Cooper  Notes If you are a fan of swing beats in jazz, and hip hop doesn&#39;t entirely disturb you, you might like Andy Cooper and crew.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Saki Kaskas</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-11-01-hello-music-playlist-saki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-11-01-hello-music-playlist-saki/</guid>
      <description>Songs: Saki Kaskamanidis: Little Sweaty Sow, Changes, Fast Lane, Prime Funk (Extended), Feta Cheese, Globular Cluster, Siwash Rock, Knossos (Remix), Saturnight, Callista, Bulbular Swirl, Fasolatha, Nashat, Powerslide, Amorphous Being, Showcase, Toxic Exhaust, Flimsy, Gore, Bleary
  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Saki Kaskamanidis  Notes Saki was straight-up a monster talent, and humble, and authentic. Listen to his music if you want to amp up your workout, get technical, or kick-it, back in the crib.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Seventies Era Jazz</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-10-20-music-playlist-jazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-10-20-music-playlist-jazz/</guid>
      <description> Songs: Donald Byrd: Flight Time*, Where are we going?, Just my Imagination, Black Jack, Design A Nation, M&amp;#39;s, Bossa (Canto G Bossa), The Dude, Places and Spaces I&amp;#39;ve Been, Lansanas Priestess, Dizzy Gillespie: Unicorn
  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Smooth Jazz   </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>