<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>non fiction on Cloud Nine</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/non-fiction/</link><description>Recent content in non fiction on Cloud Nine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/non-fiction/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>American Financier, by Jean Strous</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-28-american-financier/</link><pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-28-american-financier/</guid><description>J.P. Morgan: celebrated, powerfully unambiguous, oligarchically connected, pillar of American history. The man with the bushy
furrowed brows, pudgy fat nose, and bulging adams apple. As a school boy, he was infirm, aloof, and disliked. As a business titan his stubby fingers horned on
every corner of gilded America. He built the railway to the west. When Edison dumped Tesla on the street with a shovel - less a year or two of salary - Morgan
picked him up and put him back in the money.</description></item><item><title>Smith, Keynes, and Penrose</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-15-smith-keynes-and-penrose/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-15-smith-keynes-and-penrose/</guid><description>What do
Adam Smith, John Maynard Keynes, and Roger Penrose have in common? Well, certainly there must have been something, but it wasn't the content
of their books. Smith and Keynes were economists, Penrose is a mathematical physicist. Still, I've mentioned them here together because in a
way I'm telling a story and Roger Penrose's book is to me right now in some ways what Keynes's book once was. Let's start with me and Adam
Smith.</description></item><item><title>Business the Ultimate Resource</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-04-business-the-ultimate-resource/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-04-business-the-ultimate-resource/</guid><description>This is a
fantastic book. I bought it when it was first published (in 2002), and my copy is well used. The idea seems to be basically to publish
everything you need to know about business, that a book can teach you, between two covers. The reality of course is that there
are a lot of books on business, and many of them are inspiring and educational. Moreover, books like this one are great for people who want to
understand key processes in big business, and even helpful for those who want to build better small business, but, despite what Chekhov
said about it, business is not about processes, buzz words, or other people's money, it's about value exchange.</description></item></channel></rss>