<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>research on Cloud Nine</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/research/</link><description>Recent content in research on Cloud Nine</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Smart Government And The Data Revolution</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-19-smart-government-and-big-data/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-19-smart-government-and-big-data/</guid><description>The data revolution is impacting government in a number of ways. The foremost is known as 'smart government', which is a
reference to the way governments manage the data they have and the way they make that management and the services that go with it available
to their clients (constituents in a democracy). The second impact, also intelligent, is known as the 'smart city.'
Smart government is a concept championed by the Estonian government (our example), which won the United Nations Public
Service Award, in the category of Promoting Whole of Government Approaches in the Information Age, for their online business registry.</description></item><item><title>Research, The New Profit Center</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-15-research-new-profit-center/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-15-research-new-profit-center/</guid><description>Enhanced financial regulation typically comes with intended and unintended consequences. Directive 2004/39/EC, the Market
for Financial Instruments Directive (MiFID), for example, successfully increased competition among financial instrument trading
organizations in Europe. This brought down consumer prices and narrowed margins. It also sent market participants looking to move large
blocks of shares into dark pools, where trade data are not made public.
There will be intended and unintended consequences from MiFID's successor, MiFID2, which is anticipated to be in effect
by January 2018.</description></item><item><title>Little Firms Big Decisions</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-12-little-firms-big-decisions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-12-little-firms-big-decisions/</guid><description>Big data means billions if not trillions of observations recorded daily. Sophisticated data infrastructures
and advanced algorithms reveal new insights into our fast changing world, but only for those massive organizations with the transaction
frequency and the know how to extract them, right?
The question is one of relevance. While big data benefits for large organizations are readily tangible--like in the case
where retailers want to know when customers are more likely to purchase which products, or what optimal prices will move discounted products
in a set time frame--smaller organizations sometimes just don't see how the data revolution is important to them.</description></item><item><title>Research In The Age Of Data Science</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-10-data-science-and-research/</link><pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-10-data-science-and-research/</guid><description>Data science improves organizational function, but it isn't always cheap. Scientific data analysis enables organizations to develop more
internally efficient business systems. They can more easily reach potential stakeholders and engage them. Data informed organizations can
prepare forward, more accurately refine and refocus strategies, and more effectively manage risks. The problem is data science itself is an
investment heavy human resource, and those costs are passed on to the employer. Trainees need a strong background in probability and
statistics, and expertise in a speciality subject, like political science, medicine, engineering, or economics.</description></item><item><title>Macroeconomic Outlook</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-08-14-macroeconomic-outlook/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-08-14-macroeconomic-outlook/</guid><description>Introduction
The following article comprises my general world economic outlook. It is necessary to clarify a few points for the
reader. Firstly, the exercise is positive rather than normative. For example, any mention of oil should be read as an inchoate view of where
world oil prices, or supply and demand, may go in future periods, rather than a statement that policies should pursue increased oil output,
or that carbon fuel consumption is net surplus enhancing.</description></item><item><title>European Union Government Procurement Study</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-03-28-european-union-government-procurement-study/</link><pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-03-28-european-union-government-procurement-study/</guid><description>Abstract
This report analyzes EU-wide public procurement markets and market segments through modelling of
the EU's Tenders Electronic Daily (TED) data, among other sources, as well as the critical legal elements of the emerging EU-wide public
procurement regime. The modelling results point to procurement markets that are particularly contestable for Canadian Companies. In the fast changing world of public procurement,
the work in this paper is no longer relevant, but does provide sources for future research.</description></item><item><title>EU Canada Comprehensive Economic and Trade Agreement</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-07-eu-canada-ceta-workshop/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-07-eu-canada-ceta-workshop/</guid><description>Abstract
An analysis of procurement laws and statistics at the major levels of government across Canada.
Data collection, wrangling, modelling, research, writing, and editing by Yuri Tricys, among others. Author and Director of research, Kurt Hubner.
Download EU Canada CETA Workshop</description></item><item><title>Trade Liberalization And Sector Productivity</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</guid><description>Abstract
This paper analyzes the effects of trade liberalization on productivity at the sector level. This is
done with a multivariable regression of relative gross labour productivity on sector trade, between the
U.S. and Canada, relative to total trade, between Canada and the world. A set of before and after
treatment variables are used to distinguish the difference between the effect of trade openness before
the NAFTA preferential trade agreement and after the agreement.</description></item><item><title>A Case for Continued Pursuit of Emu Accession in Lithuania</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</guid><description>Abstract
This paper reviews arguments in academic literature for and against Lithuania's pursuit of EMU accession. The
results indicate Lithuania stands to gain in trade with ROW and with the EMU on completion of change-over to the Euro. Moreover, trade
specialization and the potential of under-trading, promise further gains from Euro accession. Economies of scale ensure that gains from
trade and currency management cost reductions will be large relative to GDP.</description></item><item><title>An Optimal Pathway To Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</title><link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</guid><description>Abstract
This paper reviews academic arguments for and against fiscal policy alignment and increased transnational budgets in the EMU. It suggests
credit market instruments are costlier than tax based transfers and the current system of structural funding is inadequate,and an enhanced
fiscal transfer system, funded from a community level tax base, is an optimal pathway toward business cycle convergence in the EMU.
Download Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</description></item></channel></rss>