<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Archives on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/archives/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Archives on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/archives/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>To Raise or Not to Raise</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</guid>
      <description>US indicators out this week, like the Chicago PMI and the CPI estimates, support both sides of a US turn-around, the output side and the consumption side. Yet still the FED, though widely expected to raise rates in the summer, remains tight-lipped about it, downplaying positive economic indicators. This sounds like policy speak for &#39;we want to keep the option in our pocket,&#39; and there is good reason. While the UK and the US have been running the money tap seemingly forever, at least since 1929 part-two, the great depression strikes back, the rest of the known world, and the unknown world, is starting to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming ECB Rate Changes</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday&#39;s flash Harmonized Consumer Price Index indicated a drop in EMU price rises to 0.5%. Given the ECB&#39;s primary target is price stability, markets are widely anticipating tomorrow&#39;s ECB meeting will see overnight interest rates reduced to negative levels.This would have banks less likely to deposit daily surpluses in the ECB overnight and more likely to loan them out. They would also commit a smaller portion of liquidity to paying down liabilities previously acquired with the ECB.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>