<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>stock market on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/stock-market/</link>
    <description>Recent content in stock market on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/stock-market/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Newton&#39;s Stock Market</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-newtons-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-newtons-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>Naturalsciences in usual circumstances are wonderfully predictable; what goes up must come down. Economists since Walras have beenpromoting the profitable illusion that economics is a natural science. Today, more than anytime in history, that charade is obviously bunk.US stocks have gone up but not down. This has analysts, traders, economists, and pretty much everyone else asking the same questions. Whyaren&#39;t they coming down? When will they? Should I buy US stocks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cobalt: Attractive, But Not Without Its Downsides</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-20-cobalt-attractive-not-without-downsides/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-20-cobalt-attractive-not-without-downsides/</guid>
      <description>The price of a metric ton of cobalt, the precious metal used in lithium batteries, increased 60% in the last year to $81,500USD, a 264% increase since its all time low in February of 2016. Higher prices have lifted present valuations of cobalt bearing propertiesand attracted capital into the metal. Typically, when a commodity booms in price supply increases until the price falls. In 2017, however,analysts predicted high prices through 2022, based on supply-side restrictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is An ETF?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-18-what-is-an-etf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-18-what-is-an-etf/</guid>
      <description>What is an ETF?Electronically traded funds are close-end funds that trade on a stock exchange. They are managed through a creation andredemption scheme that ties their contents to those of an index, or selection of investments that meet specific criteria. The value of anETF is determined by market forces. When the value deviates from the net asset value (NAV) of the underlying investments, traders trade onthe arbitrage opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallstreet&#39;s Liquidity Problem</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-22-wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-22-wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</guid>
      <description>It doesn&#39;t take a rocket scientist to see that addressing the liquidity problem on Wall Street by borrowing to restorethe ability to lend does not address the underlying aggregate debt issue.
The common sense approach says that to avoid a sudden crash or some kind of long drawn out debt deflation, the AmericanGovernment needs to address the ability of the real economy to earn, borrow and spend. And in this sense yes, much of the relief could havegone to debtors at large and not the creditors, who to pay their new debts will have to lend more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
