<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Economics on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/economics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Economics on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>American Financier, by Jean Strous</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-28-american-financier/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-28-american-financier/</guid>
      <description>J.P. Morgan: celebrated, powerfully unambiguous, oligarchicaly connected, pillar of American history. The man with the bushy furrowed brows, pudgy fat nose, and bulging adams apple. As a school boy, he was infirm, aloof, and disliked. As a business titan he had fingers in every corner of gilded America. He built the railway to the west. When Edison dumped Tesla on the street with a shovel - less a year or two of salary - Morgan signed him from his rescuers and put him back in the money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Written Good</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-04-written-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-03-04-written-good/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday wasn&#39;t a typical day. It was my birthday. I took a brush to the whiteboard and replaced all the TODOs with the words &#34;Read Python,&#34; in an extra large blue custom font I&#39;m calling &#39;meander.&#39; I packed one of the python books in with a couple of others and took the train to the library. My idea of a good time really is a quiet nook and a well written book.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smith, Keynes, and Penrose</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-15-smith-keynes-and-penrose/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/2020-02-15-smith-keynes-and-penrose/</guid>
      <description>What do Adam Smith, John Maynard Keynes, and Roger Penrose have in common? Well, certainly there must have been something, but it wasn&#39;t the content of their books. Smith and Keynes were economists, Penrose is a mathematical physicist. Still, I&#39;ve mentioned them here together because in a way I&#39;m telling a story and Roger Penrose&#39;s book is to me right now in some ways what Keynes&#39;s book once was. Let&#39;s start with me and Adam Smith.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Book Post</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/another-book-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 05 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/books/another-book-post/</guid>
      <description> The Alchemy Of Finance  And here is a code block, right? (setq whatever-variable-to t)    YOu Know    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Newton&#39;s Stock Market</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-newtons-stock-market/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-newtons-stock-market/</guid>
      <description>Natural sciences in usual circumstances are wonderfully predictable; what goes up must come down. Economists since Walras have been promoting the profitable illusion that economics is a natural science. Today, more than anytime in history, that charade is obviously bunk. US stocks have gone up but not down. This has analysts, traders, economists, and pretty much everyone else asking the same questions. Why aren&#39;t they coming down? When will they? Should I buy US stocks?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smaller Trade Deals, More Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-25-smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</guid>
      <description>Rarely have free trade debaters--on all sides--had better opportunities to wag tongues. The long-standing era of free trade deals that in Canada started with the Canada-US Free Trade Agreement in 1987 (CUSFTA), superseded by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) in 1994, has run squarely into a pronounced US protectionist revival that glaringly threatens the now deeply integrated global trade regime. This is not, by the way, an uncontested protectionist movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>When Harry Met Sally</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-23-time-value-of-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-23-time-value-of-money/</guid>
      <description>What is the Best Age To Invest? According to value investors, like Warren Buffet, the secret sauce of finance can be explained in five simple words:
Investing is all about timing. The five simple words that contain the secret to investing like a billionaire are: The time value of money. While money doesn&#39;t exactly grow on trees, it does actually grow like a tree-a big, green, Christmasy [acceptable?], money tree. Yes, most people eventually learn the sheer power of savings and compound interest, but few people learn it early enough to use it wisely.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is An ETF?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-18-what-is-an-etf/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 18 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-18-what-is-an-etf/</guid>
      <description>What is an ETF? Electronically traded funds are close-end funds that trade on a stock exchange. They are managed through a creation and redemption scheme that ties their contents to those of an index, or selection of investments that meet specific criteria. The value of an ETF is determined by market forces. When the value deviates from the net asset value (NAV) of the underlying investments, traders trade on the arbitrage opportunity.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should I stay Or Should I Go?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-12-should-i-stay-or-should-i-go/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-02-12-should-i-stay-or-should-i-go/</guid>
      <description>Despite what some people will tell you, the recent sell-off in the stock market was not a result of rising bond yields (as I said before rising bond yields are more likely to have delayed the sell-off). Yes, bond yields now are more volatile, and so are stocks; and yes, money moving between the two and from the sidelines has an impact on that volatility; but, there are two stronger theories, in my opinion, explaining the sell-off now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blog Links</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-01-01-economics-blog-links/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-01-01-economics-blog-links/</guid>
      <description>Ben Bernake&amp;rsquo;s Blog
CEPR BLOG
Central Bank News
Paul Krugman New York Times
Dr. Ed&amp;rsquo;s Blog
Econ Browser
Equitable Growth
Guru Focus
Lazy Economist
Liberty Street Economics
Macro Blog Fed Atlanta
Money Beat
Multiplier Effect
Grumpy Economist
Vox
Zauzel 100
Zero Hedge
Naked Capitalism</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Economic Policy</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-30-what-is-economic-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-30-what-is-economic-policy/</guid>
      <description>What is economic policy? If economics can be described as the study of the allocation of scarce resources among agents, economic policy can be described as the public rules and regulations that guide that allocation. Wherever a society is governed with laws, there will be laws that influence the economic prosperity of constituents, producers, and suppliers, as well as the distribution of resources among agents within the economy. Those rules constitute economic policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Macroeconomics</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-19-what-are-macroeconomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-19-what-are-macroeconomics/</guid>
      <description>What is macroeconomics Macroeconomics is the field of economics that deals with aggregated quantities. Microeconomics, for example, might deal with firm level economics, while macroeconomics might deal with aggregate firms level economics, the economics of all the firms in an economy together. Macroeconomics therefore includes the study of national level and supranational level economics.
What kind of indicators are macroeconomic? Macroeconomic indicators include trade indicators, like the trade balance, and trade openness, but also indicators that describe other facets of the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Where Is The Money?</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-12-03-where-is-the-money/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-12-03-where-is-the-money/</guid>
      <description>As Krugman might say, &#34;...it&#39;s in the market, stupid.&#34; The most influential economy in the world is poised to raise interest rates, but not because of inflation. Central banks in major parts of the world are still at the zero bound, and core prices are behaving as they should when targeted only because liquidity is trapped on balance sheets as inventory. What happened? Why did monetary easing take half a decade to jump-start the US dollar economy?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BIS Warns of Low Rates</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-06-28-bis-warns-of-low-rates/</guid>
      <description>The Bank of International Settlements (BIS) continues to reprimand contemporary central banking culture for easy money fixes it argues feed instability by creating global economic conditions that foster bubbles. As the story goes, demand side policies are band-aids slapped on top of deep structural wounds. This is especially the case in a world where financial intermediation dominates money channels with a vast array of levers, ropes, and pulleys that push the lag between easing and higher demand more and more unmeasurably into the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>To Raise or Not to Raise</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-02-26-to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Feb 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2015-02-26-to-raise-or-not-to-raise/</guid>
      <description>US indicators out this week, like the Chicago PMI and the CPI estimates, support both sides of a US turn-around, the output side and the consumption side. Yet still the FED, though widely expected to raise rates in the summer, remains tight-lipped about it, downplaying positive economic indicators. This sounds like policy speak for &#39;we want to keep the option in our pocket,&#39; and there is good reason. While the UK and the US have been running the money tap seemingly forever, at least since 1929 part-two, the great depression strikes back, the rest of the known world, and the unknown world, is starting to catch up.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upcoming ECB Rate Changes</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2014-06-04-upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2014-06-04-upcoming-ecb-rate-changes/</guid>
      <description>Yesterday&#39;s flash Harmonized Consumer Price Index indicated a drop in EMU price rises to 0.5%. Given the ECB&#39;s primary target is price stability, markets are widely anticipating tomorrow&#39;s ECB meeting will see overnight interest rates reduced to negative levels.This would have banks less likely to deposit daily surpluses in the ECB overnight and more likely to loan them out. They would also commit a smaller portion of liquidity to paying down liabilities previously acquired with the ECB.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Macroeconomic Outlook</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-08-14-macroeconomic-outlook/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-08-14-macroeconomic-outlook/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The following article comprises my general world economic outlook. It is necessary to clarify a few points for the reader. Firstly, the exercise is positive rather than normative. For example, any mention of oil should be read as an inchoate view of where world oil prices, or supply and demand, may go in future periods, rather than a statement that policies should pursue increased oil output, or that carbon fuel consumption is net surplus enhancing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>European Union Government Procurement Study</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-03-28-european-union-government-procurement-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2013-03-28-european-union-government-procurement-study/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This report analyzes EU-wide public procurement markets and market segments through modelling of the EU&#39;s Tenders Electronic Daily (TED) data, among other sources, as well as the critical legal elements of the emerging EU-wide public procurement regime. The modelling results point to procurement markets that are particularly contestable for Canadian Companies. In the fast changing world of public procurement, the work in this paper is no longer relevant, but does provide sources for future research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>EU Canada Comprehensive Economic and Trade Agreement</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-07-eu-canada-ceta-workshop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-07-eu-canada-ceta-workshop/</guid>
      <description>Abstract An analysis of procurement laws and statistics at the major levels of government across Canada. Data collection, wrangling, modelling, research, writing, and editing by Yuri Tricys, among others. Author and Director of research, Kurt Hubner.  
Download EU Canada CETA Workshop</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Liberalization And Sector Productivity</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper analyzes the effects of trade liberalization on productivity at the sector level. This is done with a multivariable regression of relative gross labour productivity on sector trade, between the U.S. and Canada, relative to total trade, between Canada and the world. A set of before and after treatment variables are used to distinguish the difference between the effect of trade openness before the NAFTA preferential trade agreement and after the agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case for Continued Pursuit of Emu Accession in Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper reviews arguments in academic literature for and against Lithuania&#39;s pursuit of EMU accession. The results indicate Lithuania stands to gain in trade with ROW and with the EMU on completion of change-over to the Euro. Moreover, trade specialization and the potential of under-trading, promise further gains from Euro accession. Economies of scale ensure that gains from trade and currency management cost reductions will be large relative to GDP.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An Optimal Pathway To Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-02-26-optimal-pathway-to-business-cycle-convergence-in-the-emu/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper reviews academic arguments for and against fiscal policy alignment and increased transnational budgets in the EMU. It suggests credit market instruments are costlier than tax based transfers and the current system of structural funding is inadequate,and an enhanced fiscal transfer system, funded from a community level tax base, is an optimal pathway toward business cycle convergence in the EMU.  
Download Business Cycle Convergence In The EMU</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Strong Dollar Could Be Good For Canada</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-11-28-strong-dollar-could-be-good-for-canada/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-11-28-strong-dollar-could-be-good-for-canada/</guid>
      <description>Pundits of the double-dip recession theory cite the now globally anticipated fallout of the U.S. dollar as a key source. The fed is printing money like confetti, they say. The U.S. Treasury bill bubble is soon to pop, they add. The newly coined (U.S. dollar-carry trade) (it used to be the yen-carry trade) is driving commodities through the roof, they squeal. The concerns are many. For example, rampant increases in U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing With The HST</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-09-15-dealing-with-the-hst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2009-09-15-dealing-with-the-hst/</guid>
      <description>Protests across the province last month made it clear to British Columbians that the PST/GST harmonization announced on July 23 by Premier Gordon Campbell is not going over well. Former Premier Bill Vander Zalm grasped onto the issue like a life raft, presumably hoping to resurrect his long-thought dead but apparently still alive Social Credit initiatives. The NDP are joining Mr. Vander Zalm in the attack on the provincial Liberal for, perhaps, partisan reasons (it&#39;s worth nothing that New Democrats in prairies support the HST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Down The House</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-12-04-bringing-down-the-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-12-04-bringing-down-the-house/</guid>
      <description>What ever happened to Canadian government for all Canadians? Clearly out the window. Whatever happened to non-partisan politics? Has there ever been such a thing? Do we really need an economic stimulus package, or is the recent uproar in the House of Commons little more than partisan on partisan? Will a coalition government serve the people well? Is democracy being put to the test?
Well, it&#39;s not much, but technically an increase in newspaper sales should cause an increase in GDP, and if one opens the paper it&#39;s hard not to imagine an increase in newspaper sales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Bell, Business And State Tie The knot.</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-11-30-wedding-bells-business-and-state-tie-the-knot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-11-30-wedding-bells-business-and-state-tie-the-knot/</guid>
      <description>Last month, before U.S. election results, I was chatting with a friend about economic political history. He wrote a line that stuck with me. He wrote (Western civilization has got to stop patting itself on the back for separating church and state and get on with the business of separating business and state.) At the time I thought the line might one day just come off (I was thinking of receding lobbyist influence given the likelihood of a democrat government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Tories At The Table, More Water In The Liberal Hull</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-26-more-tories-at-the-table-more-water-in-the-liberal-hull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-26-more-tories-at-the-table-more-water-in-the-liberal-hull/</guid>
      <description>Was it Warren Buffet who reminded us of the irrationality in the stock market? What was it he said, stock markets are people driven and people are irrational? I&#39;d like to add the movements of populist governments to his irrational people bit as, it seems to me, both populist governments and stock markets are guided by public opinion. If public opinion is an expression of human behavior, (run that one by your local shrink if you like,) does that make it the result of feelings, instincts, and herd-like responses to media induced perceptions (not a herd of hippo&#39;s mind you, that&#39;s the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stimulating Interest</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-24-stimulating-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-24-stimulating-interest/</guid>
      <description>So world leaders (note: 20 of them) have agreed to come together in a first ever meeting of the G20 to discuss a restructuring of global financial market systems. Finally, economic and politically minded people everywhere are revisiting the decisions that have shaped our global economy into the fertile soil for crisis that it has become.
Milton Friedman&#39;s legacy is under attack. The concepts of nationalism and socialism in the state are not only being reconsidered, they are being re-instituted as we speak (the nationalization of big banks globally).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallstreet&#39;s Liquidity Problem</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-22-wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2008-09-22-wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</guid>
      <description>It doesn&#39;t take a rocket scientist to see that addressing the liquidity problem on Wall Street by borrowing to restore the ability to lend does not address the underlying aggregate debt issue.
The common sense approach says that to avoid a sudden crash or some kind of long drawn out debt deflation, the American Government needs to address the ability of the real economy to earn, borrow and spend. And in this sense yes, much of the relief could have gone to debtors at large and not the creditors, who to pay their new debts will have to lend more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>