<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Business on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/business/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Business on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Alignment Through Communication</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-01-30-achieving-alignment-through-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-01-30-achieving-alignment-through-communication/</guid>
      <description>Psychologists do important work, but it doesn&#39;t take one to know that people operate a lot like computers. We&#39;ve got code inside that issues a response when stimulated. The more you know the person, the more you know what responses to expect. In any organization team building improves organizational outcomes. But what is going on when team members bond?
Alignment is a concept that explains what&#39;s going on. Let each line in this chart represent a person; but more than that, let it represent their psychology, the millions of associations their mind contains between images and expectations, words and definitions, and information and responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research, The New Profit Center</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-15-research-new-profit-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-15-research-new-profit-center/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced financial regulation typically comes with intended and unintended consequences. Directive 2004/39/EC, the Market for Financial Instruments Directive (MiFID), for example, successfully increased competition among financial instrument trading organizations in Europe. This brought down consumer prices and narrowed margins. It also sent market participants looking to move large blocks of shares into dark pools, where trade data are not made public.
There will be intended and unintended consequences from MiFID&#39;s successor, MiFID2, which is anticipated to be in effect by January 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Psychology</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Numerous studies have examined what intangible and tangible factors might cause one organization to outperform others over a period of time. There is no question that ideas and talent are invaluable, but it is no longer any surprise that the single most important factor affecting organizational performance is organizational psychology. Here are a few examples:
Ray Dalio runs Bridgewater Associates, one of the largest hedge funds in the world. In Connecticut, he&#39;s got 1500 people, some of whom are the best and brightest brains in the financial sector, but does Ray cite his PhDs, research acumen, and process as his number one a comparative advantage?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science And The Law</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-08-data-science-and-the-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-08-data-science-and-the-law/</guid>
      <description>Information technologies and the data they create are changing the world rapidly in a multitude of ways. The legal profession, one of the most traditional and adverse to change, is beginning to adapt. A new breed of data savvy lawyers are entering legal circles everywhere and bringing with them an inertia from new technologies.
Firstly, the legal profession stands to gain from those data driven insights that are common across organizations, like more accurately targeted marketing, more informed case selection, more efficient internal procedures, and pricing models that minimize both losses of producer surplus, and dead-weight losses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet Of Things</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-04-the-internet-of-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-04-the-internet-of-things/</guid>
      <description>The Internet of things (IOT) is a reference to computerization in devices and machines we use in everyday life. Smart homes and the smart appliances in them are examples of things that are more and more frequently connected to the Internet and programmable with computers. Online appliances transmit sensory information upstream to computer processors that make decisions, like adjusting the heat, turning on or off a hot water tank, switching up power sources, or charging electronic devices, like cars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Statistics And Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-23-trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-23-trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>National and international level statistics that report macroeconomic indicators, like nominal and real inflation, international transaction flows, and trade statistics, are relied on by market participants, policy makers and stakeholders as inputs to critical decisions. More often than not, macroeconomic statistics are taken as reliable, after-all, those are our official statistics, right?. But just how reliable are they? Unfortunately, the answer is that aligning statistics with underlying realities is a challenging task, and mainstream macroeconomic statistics should, even in the best of cases, be taken with a grain of salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Firms Big Decisions</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-12-little-firms-big-decisions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-12-little-firms-big-decisions/</guid>
      <description>Big data means billions if not trillions of observations recorded daily. Sophisticated data infrastructures and advanced algorithms reveal new insights into our fast changing world, but only for those massive organizations with the transaction frequency and the know how to extract them, right?
The question is one of relevance. While big data benefits for large organizations are readily tangible--like in the case where retailers want to know when customers are more likely to purchase which products, or what optimal prices will move discounted products in a set time frame--smaller organizations sometimes just don&#39;t see how the data revolution is important to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Economic Policy</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-30-what-is-economic-policy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-30-what-is-economic-policy/</guid>
      <description>What is economic policy? If economics can be described as the study of the allocation of scarce resources among agents, economic policy can be described as the public rules and regulations that guide that allocation. Wherever a society is governed with laws, there will be laws that influence the economic prosperity of constituents, producers, and suppliers, as well as the distribution of resources among agents within the economy. Those rules constitute economic policy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Maths Programming</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-25-what-is-maths-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-25-what-is-maths-programming/</guid>
      <description>What is maths programming? Mathematical programming, or computational programming, is the process of translating mathematically representable problems into computer languages then harnessing the power of computers to solve them. Along with the Internet, and task facilitation, mathematical programming is probably the most important contribution from the modern computer to human evolution. There are many kinds of mathematical programming techniques. Among these are: linear and non-linear programming, integer programming, mixed complementary problems, networks, goal programming, multiple objective optimization, queuing theory, regression analysis, and many more.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Decision Analysis</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-23-what-is-decision-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-23-what-is-decision-analysis/</guid>
      <description>What is decision analysis? Decision analysis is a subcategory of decision science. Ultimately, all data science could be classified as decision science, because the entire point of data analytics and informatics is to enable better decision making processes to yield better outcomes from decisions. While decision science and decision analysis cannot eliminate the possibility of sub-optimal outcomes, they are in themselves useful if not mandatory processes. They can, for example, enable teams or decision makers to move forward with confidence in their assessments of decision variable behaviour across decision parameters, and thus with more reasonable expectation of probable outcomes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Optimization</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-21-what-is-optimization/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-21-what-is-optimization/</guid>
      <description>What is optimization Optimization is about making choices that lead to first best outcomes. Mathematically, optimization is usually described with differential calculus, though when functions are linear, and problems are adequately fit substitution can lead to optimal solutions. In mathematics, optimization first requires the delineation of an objective function, a dependent function meant to be maximized or minimized through variations in the independent functions that predict it. Solving optimization problems therefore requires identifying maximum or minimum points on the objective function and qualifying those points as local or global maximums or minimums.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is International Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-01-18-what-is-internation-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2018-01-18-what-is-internation-trade/</guid>
      <description>What is international trade? International trade is the movement of goods across national borders. Because bilateral exchange rates change frequently, international trade is watched closely by national and supranational governments. Small changes in currency pair spreads can impact the movement of goods across borders and, as a consequence, the health of a nation&#39;s domestic industry and its employment levels.
How do organizations measure international trade? Physical goods (commodity trade) are tracked by governments when they enter various economic and trade zones within an economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Modelling</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-14-what-is-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-14-what-is-modelling/</guid>
      <description>What is modelling? Modelling is an important part of decision science. Modellers make simplified representations of reality to produce judgements about reality and guide real decisions. Models can be abstract and theoretical, or data driven and empirical. Both categories can be prescriptive, predictive, or descriptive.
Why model? Modelling is a cost-effective way to test the successes and failures of potential projects without committing large-scale resources. Modelling is also useful as means of building support necessary to successfully launch projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Data Wrangling</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-08-what-is-data-wrangling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-08-what-is-data-wrangling/</guid>
      <description>What is data wrangling? Data wrangling is the process of preparing data for analysis or computation. It includes transforming data into various formats and statistical derivations, cleaning data to account for missing observations, clumsy data types, or outright errors, and arranging data into workable categorized data sets.
When should data be cleaned? Anyone working with data knows it needs to be cleaned many times along the data pipeline. After data is collected, it must be wrangled before it is stored.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Data Science</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-03-what-is-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-03-what-is-data-science/</guid>
      <description>What is data science? The science of data promises to change the world, but many of us do not know what data science is. This segement gives you our answer.
Data science is the science of data analytics in the context of scientific query. The data scientist first asks scientific questions, then gathers data relevant to those questions, and finally applies a variety of computer processes and statistical and probabilistic theories to derive answers to those questions.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>