<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyrights</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Installation and Defaults</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/emacs-installation-and-defaults/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/emacs-installation-and-defaults/</guid>
      <description>Directly below are the subheadings to the first main heading of my initialization file, see my last post Emacs Configuration Overview. I&#39;ll go through the lines of code in order, but remember, the line numbers you see in Hugo&#39;s code block css styling are relative to the code on this page not the emacs initialization file [Hugo is the Static Content Management System based on GO I used to make this blog].</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Configuration Overview</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/emacs-configuration-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/emacs-configuration-overview/</guid>
      <description>Below are some notes covering among other things why I got into Emacs, where I got my version, and how my configuration is organized. As mentioned before, other text editors in use today, like Atom, IntelliJ Idea, or Sublime Text are awesome, and offer also great selections of unique packages. Atom, for example, has some super useful snippet packages. You can convert them into Yasnippet format (an Emacs snippet package), but it&#39;s a hassle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Windows Program Launcher</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/windows-program-launcher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/windows-program-launcher/</guid>
      <description>For any readers setting up configuration files for their emacs editor, here is the quick and easy code for the windows program launcher shown in the image below.    Here&amp;rsquo;s the config code: 
1 2 3 4 5 6 7  ;path of program you want in your launcher (defvar name-of-program-p &amp;#34;C:/full-path-to-program/program.exe&amp;#34;) ; launcher function (defun launch-program-name () (interactive) (w32-shell-execute nil name-of-program-p nil) );end launch-program-name    Then you can put the launch function name in your hydra config, like this:  (&amp;quot;p&amp;quot; launch-program-name &amp;quot;Launch This Program&amp;quot;)  For the generate hydra code see this post: Emacs Bookmarks  Thanks for reading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Emacs Bookmarks</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/emacs-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/emacs-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Jumping To Directories In Emacs  If you want to accomplish things efficiently with your computer, you will benefit from mastering a text editor. I use emacs as a general project manager for web development, writing, and organizing thoughts, materials, and actions. Jumping to and from directories and files enables quickly me to get things done more efficiently. To do this I use a few different packages and functions. They are:</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>