<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Data Science on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/data-science/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Data Science on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/data-science/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data And Output, The Second Wave</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-and-output/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-and-output/</guid>
      <description>The communications revolution is no longer promising to shift production possibility frontiers outwardly, it is doing so rapidly. But there is a second shift we have not seen yet, and that&#39;s the big data shift. The capacity for organizations to improve decisions by rendering the changing digital footprint into meaningful direction, is going to reduce economic distortions in a number of ways. Firms will be able to match customers with products more efficiently.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Smart Government And The Data Revolution</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smart-government-and-big-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smart-government-and-big-data/</guid>
      <description>The data revolution is impacting government in a number of ways. The foremost is known as &#39;smart government&#39;, which is a reference to the way governments manage the data they have and the way they make that management and the services that go with it available to their clients (constituents in a democracy). The second impact, also intelligent, is known as the &#39;smart city.&#39;
Smart government is a concept championed by the Estonian government (our example), which won the United Nations Public Service Award, in the category of Promoting Whole of Government Approaches in the Information Age, for their online business registry.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research, The New Profit Center</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/research-new-profit-center/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/research-new-profit-center/</guid>
      <description>Enhanced financial regulation typically comes with intended and unintended consequences. Directive 2004/39/EC, the Market for Financial Instruments Directive (MiFID), for example, successfully increased competition among financial instrument trading organizations in Europe. This brought down consumer prices and narrowed margins. It also sent market participants looking to move large blocks of shares into dark pools, where trade data are not made public.
There will be intended and unintended consequences from MiFID&#39;s successor, MiFID2, which is anticipated to be in effect by January 2018.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science And The Law</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-science-and-the-law/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-science-and-the-law/</guid>
      <description>Information technologies and the data they create are changing the world rapidly in a multitude of ways. The legal profession, one of the most traditional and adverse to change, is beginning to adapt. A new breed of data savvy lawyers are entering legal circles everywhere and bringing with them an inertia from new technologies.
Firstly, the legal profession stands to gain from those data driven insights that are common across organizations, like more accurately targeted marketing, more informed case selection, more efficient internal procedures, and pricing models that minimize both losses of producer surplus, and dead-weight losses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Internet Of Things</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/the-internet-of-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/the-internet-of-things/</guid>
      <description>The Internet of things (IOT) is a reference to computerization in devices and machines we use in everyday life. Smart homes and the smart appliances in them are examples of things that are more and more frequently connected to the Internet and programmable with computers. Online appliances transmit sensory information upstream to computer processors that make decisions, like adjusting the heat, turning on or off a hot water tank, switching up power sources, or charging electronic devices, like cars.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Statistics And Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>National and international level statistics that report macroeconomic indicators, like nominal and real inflation, international transaction flows, and trade statistics, are relied on by market participants, policy makers and stakeholders as inputs to critical decisions. More often than not, macroeconomic statistics are taken as reliable, after-all, those are our official statistics, right?. But just how reliable are they? Unfortunately, the answer is that aligning statistics with underlying realities is a challenging task, and mainstream macroeconomic statistics should, even in the best of cases, be taken with a grain of salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Data Science</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-data-science/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-data-science/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Little Firms Big Decisions</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-needs-and-firm-size/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-needs-and-firm-size/</guid>
      <description>Big data means billions if not trillions of observations recorded daily. Sophisticated data infrastructures and advanced algorithms reveal new insights into our fast changing world, but only for those massive organizations with the transaction frequency and the know how to extract them, right?
The question is one of relevance. While big data benefits for large organizations are readily tangible--like in the case where retailers want to know when customers are more likely to purchase which products, or what optimal prices will move discounted products in a set time frame--smaller organizations sometimes just don&#39;t see how the data revolution is important to them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Research In The Age Of Data Science</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-science-and-research/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/data-science-and-research/</guid>
      <description>Data science improves organizational function, but it isn&#39;t always cheap. Scientific data analysis enables organizations to develop more internally efficient business systems. They can more easily reach potential stakeholders and engage them. Data informed organizations can prepare forward, more accurately refine and refocus strategies, and more effectively manage risks. The problem is data science itself is an investment heavy human resource, and those costs are passed on to the employer. Trainees need a strong background in probability and statistics, and expertise in a speciality subject, like political science, medicine, engineering, or economics.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>