<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>featured on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/featured/</link>
    <description>Recent content in featured on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/featured/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Developing Cognitive Ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-25-developing-cognitive-ambidexterity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-25-developing-cognitive-ambidexterity/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s motivational video is about the benefits of cognitive ambidexterity, why you should take some time to work on that each week, and how you can do that.
 For those of you that come here for my emacs posts, don&#39;t worry, nothing has changed. I have been working onmultidisciplinary studies for over twenty years. I routinely work at several types of activities. These include psychology work, finance,data science, computer programming, writing, and now also vlogging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Use And Configure The Emacs Text Editor, An Overview</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-01-19-emacs-configuration-overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2020-01-19-emacs-configuration-overview/</guid>
      <description>Updated March 18, 2021Loading EmacsEmacs users write custom code for their software. Each &#39;configuration&#39; can be highly individualized. Because some custom configurations take longer to load than others, Emacs users like to minimize and measure their &#39;load&#39; time.
The software loads like any other software, loading libraries included in the core, and then additional libraries according to various configuration files. With Emacs, these files are stored in various locations based on the settings specified by the user, and the system Emacs is installed on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Use And Configure Emacs Bookmark Packages</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2019-10-20-emacs-bookmarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/science/2019-10-20-emacs-bookmarks/</guid>
      <description>Updated March 18, 2021Most of my code has changed a lot recently. Check updated posts.
For each post can update code listed in that post.Keep in mind code for linux and wsl configs will have their own posts,except in the case of .early-init and init.el, which have systemswitches (to load system specific dot-files).
Also note: abandoned convention of listing initlines. Now if you want to find the code, and there is now plentyof decent emacs code, use the search function.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
