<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>personal-development on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/personal-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in personal-development on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/personal-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Spring Time. We&#39;re Doing Great.</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-03-19-global-progress-is-on-the-rise/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-03-19-global-progress-is-on-the-rise/</guid>
      <description>Today I took the train around town and ran some errands. There&#39;s an apocalypse. There were a lot of unhappy people in the streets. Rephrase that. Everyone in the street appeared unhappy. I understand. It&#39;s a pandemic.
One of my Facebook readers responded to my last post about Julian Assange. Why so serious? What&#39;s all this posting about war?
I understand. Doom and gloom subjects weigh our spirits down. A politician once told me you can&#39;t change the world, you can only squeeze it to get what you want out of it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developing Cognitive Ambidexterity</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-25-developing-cognitive-ambidexterity/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-02-25-developing-cognitive-ambidexterity/</guid>
      <description>Today&#39;s motivational video is about the benefits of cognitive ambidexterity, why you should take some time to work on that each week, and how you can do that.
    For those of you that come here for my emacs posts, don&#39;t worry, nothing has changed. I have been working on multidisciplinary studies for over twenty years. I routinely work at several types of activities. These include psychology work, finance, data science, computer programming, writing, and now also vlogging.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Achieving Alignment Through Communication</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-01-30-achieving-alignment-through-communication/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-01-30-achieving-alignment-through-communication/</guid>
      <description>Psychologists do important work, but it doesn&#39;t take one to know that people operate a lot like computers. We&#39;ve got code inside that issues a response when stimulated. The more you know the person, the more you know what responses to expect. In any organization team building improves organizational outcomes. But what is going on when team members bond?
Alignment is a concept that explains what&#39;s going on. Let each line in this chart represent a person; but more than that, let it represent their psychology, the millions of associations their mind contains between images and expectations, words and definitions, and information and responses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life Moves Habits Tell You Where</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-15-life-moves-habits-tell-you-where/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-15-life-moves-habits-tell-you-where/</guid>
      <description>Habits can be bad, like when they deter progress toward your current set of goals, and they can be good, like when they move you closer to your goals or align you with them (if, for example, your goal is to attain a certain state of being). Habits include things like the way you spend your time, the way you think about things, and the way you communicate. They determine where you are going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Bean Machine</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-07-the-bean-machine/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-09-07-the-bean-machine/</guid>
      <description>Staying Focused On Being Yourself Here is something to think about. What does it mean to be normal?
The picture below is a picture of a bean machine,  also known as a Quincunx,  a Dalton Board,  or Plinko. 
What happens to the ball when it gets dropped into the top of the bean machine? It gets bounced around right? Does the ball get to choose in which slot it will end up?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-11-12-principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-11-12-principles/</guid>
      <description>It is honorable to respect all peoples, given they are not acting outside the social contract, nor seeking to usurp unjustly another&#39;s rights or freedoms.
The law protects people in societies and enables societies to function. To the extent it remains to do so, it should be upheld at every turn. When there are laws that do not serve all citizens in a society equally, those laws should be challenged and amended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Psychology</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Numerous studies have examined what intangible and tangible factors might cause one organization to outperform others over a period of time. There is no question that ideas and talent are invaluable, but it is no longer any surprise that the single most important factor affecting organizational performance is organizational psychology. Here are a few examples:
Ray Dalio runs Bridgewater Associates, one of the largest hedge funds in the world. In Connecticut, he&#39;s got 1500 people, some of whom are the best and brightest brains in the financial sector, but does Ray cite his PhDs, research acumen, and process as his number one a comparative advantage?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Psychology -</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2016-03-10-organizational-psychology-m/</guid>
      <description>Numerous studies have examined what intangible and tangible factors might cause one organization to outperform others over a period of time. There is no question that ideas and talent are invaluable, but it is no longer any surprise that the single most important factor affecting organizational performance is organizational psychology. Here are a few examples:
Ray Dalio runs Bridgewater Associates, one of the largest hedge funds in the world. In Connecticut, he&#39;s got 1500 people, some of whom are the best and brightest brains in the financial sector, but does Ray cite his PhDs, research acumen, and process as his number one a comparative advantage?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics Of A Winner</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-15-characteristics-of-a-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2012-12-15-characteristics-of-a-winner/</guid>
      <description>Innovative Hard working Believes in what he/she is doing Focuses on details Maintains a calm and relaxed presence Well spoken (concise&amp;hellip;excellent word choice) In-it-to-win-it Responsible Intelligent Continually developing Keeps moving to the front Gets as much perspective as possible Accepts where he/she is at Lets go of errors Genuine Thorough Dutiful Light-hearted, fun Prepared Attentive Implements systems for thoughts and actions Takes action as often as possible Creative Prioritizes actions to optimal Makes time for relationships Presents value and credentials when criticized Expects attacks from others but does not hold this against them Doesn&amp;rsquo;t take life personally Courteous Engages with different social groups without owning differences Maintains a well tuned psychology Limits unprepared actions Integrates self-checking processes Keeps a narrow focus to maintain effectiveness Doesn&amp;rsquo;t flinch at criticism (nor own it) Doesn&amp;rsquo;t spin, stretch the truth or lie Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sink to a lower level Accepts the behaviour of others with humour keen Discusses what successful actions he/she is doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics Of A Winner -</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2012-12-15-characteristics-of-a-winner-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2012-12-15-characteristics-of-a-winner-m/</guid>
      <description>Innovative Hard working Believes in what he/she is doing Focuses on details Maintains a calm and relaxed presence Well spoken (concise&amp;hellip;excellent word choice) In-it-to-win-it Responsible Intelligent Continually developing Keeps moving to the front Gets as much perspective as possible Accepts where he/she is at Lets go of errors Genuine Thorough Dutiful Light-hearted, fun Prepared Attentive Implements systems for thoughts and actions Takes action as often as possible Creative Prioritizes actions to optimal Makes time for relationships Presents value and credentials when criticized Expects attacks from others but does not hold this against them Doesn&amp;rsquo;t take life personally Courteous Engages with different social groups without owning differences Maintains a well tuned psychology Limits unprepared actions Integrates self-checking processes Keeps a narrow focus to maintain effectiveness Doesn&amp;rsquo;t flinch at criticism (nor own it) Doesn&amp;rsquo;t spin, stretch the truth or lie Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sink to a lower level Accepts the behaviour of others with humour keen Discusses what successful actions he/she is doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress: Getting Along In Life</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2010-12-12-getting-along-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2010-12-12-getting-along-in-life/</guid>
      <description>Inspiration is about being on the upswing. Find out what gets you there, find out what keeps you there, and make a habit of it. Success is about a good nights sleep, either tomorrow is Sunday or you are prepared to meet it. Self-improvement is a lifestyle. Expectations are so yesterday. Grey area is dangerous. Make sure you spell it out. Prodigality is tiresome. Habits are the measuring stick you are looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress: Getting Along In Life -</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2010-12-12-getting-along-in-life-m/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2010-12-12-getting-along-in-life-m/</guid>
      <description>Inspiration is about being on the upswing. Find out what gets you there, find out what keeps you there, and make a habit of it. Success is about a good nights sleep, either tomorrow is Sunday or you are prepared to meet it. Self-improvement is a lifestyle. Expectations are so yesterday. Grey area is dangerous. Make sure you spell it out. Prodigality is tiresome. Habits are the measuring stick you are looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>