<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Politics on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/politics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Politics on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/politics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Smaller Trade Deals, More Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</guid>
      <description>Rarely have free trade debaters--on all sides--had better opportunities to wag tongues. The long-standing era of free trade deals that in Canada started with the Canada-US Free Trade Agreement in 1987 (CUSFTA), superseded by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) in 1994, has run squarely into a pronounced US protectionist revival that glaringly threatens the now deeply integrated global trade regime. This is not, by the way, an uncontested protectionist movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/principles/</guid>
      <description>It is honorable to respect all peoples, given they are not acting outside the social contract, nor seeking to usurp unjustly another&#39;s rights or freedoms.
The law protects people in societies and enables societies to function. To the extent it remains to do so, it should be upheld at every turn. When there are laws that do not serve all citizens in a society equally, those laws should be challenged and amended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Paul Krugman Weighs In On Bernie Sanders Here:</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/paul-krugman-weighs-in-on-bernie-sanders/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/paul-krugman-weighs-in-on-bernie-sanders/</guid>
      <description>There is a 90% chance Hillary will win the Democratic nomination, Paul Krugman says, so Bernie has a responsibility to support Democrats and go easier on Hillary. Paul Krugman, &amp;ldquo;Feel The Math&amp;rdquo;
This is a tell-tale sign America as an institution is standing around scratching its head about the Bernie problem. What happens if Bernie hits the tipping point?
Here&#39;s what happens if Bernie Sanders goes to the White House: America stops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill That Sank Ignatieff Looks Likely to Float</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bill-sank-ignatieff-likely-to-float/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bill-sank-ignatieff-likely-to-float/</guid>
      <description>Remember last October? Under Stephane Dion, the Liberals were, by no small margin, consistently behind the Conservatives in the national public opinion polls. Then the Conservatives released their economic update and political mayhem ensued. Stephane, Jack and Gille went up the hill and planned a coalition coupe. Stephan Harper set a frighteningly partisan political precedent by proroguing parliament when the conservatives were facing an election they looked likely to lose. And, after Mr.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dealing With The HST</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/dealing-with-the-hst/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Oct 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/dealing-with-the-hst/</guid>
      <description>Protests across the province last month made it clear to British Columbians that the PST/GST harmonization announced on July 23 by Premier Gordon Campbell is not going over well. Former Premier Bill Vander Zalm grasped onto the issue like a life raft, presumably hoping to resurrect his long-thought dead but apparently still alive Social Credit initiatives. The NDP are joining Mr. Vander Zalm in the attack on the provincial Liberal for, perhaps, partisan reasons (it&#39;s worth nothing that New Democrats in prairies support the HST).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing Down The House</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bringing-down-the-house/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/bringing-down-the-house/</guid>
      <description>What ever happened to Canadian government for all Canadians? Clearly out the window. Whatever happened to non-partisan politics? Has there ever been such a thing? Do we really need an economic stimulus package, or is the recent uproar in the House of Commons little more than partisan on partisan? Will a coalition government serve the people well? Is democracy being put to the test?
Well, it&#39;s not much, but technically an increase in newspaper sales should cause an increase in GDP, and if one opens the paper it&#39;s hard not to imagine an increase in newspaper sales.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wedding Bell, Business And State Tie The knot.</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/wedding-bells-business-and-state-tie-the-knot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/wedding-bells-business-and-state-tie-the-knot/</guid>
      <description>Last month, before U.S. election results, I was chatting with a friend about economic political history. He wrote a line that stuck with me. He wrote (Western civilization has got to stop patting itself on the back for separating church and state and get on with the business of separating business and state.) At the time I thought the line might one day just come off (I was thinking of receding lobbyist influence given the likelihood of a democrat government.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Great Debate Revisited</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/the-great-debate-revisited/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Nov 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/the-great-debate-revisited/</guid>
      <description>Okay, Obama is in the news, he&#39;s made friends, he&#39;s made headlines, he&#39;s made history-he&#39;s everywhere. The world stands in awe. Democracy has been authenticated. It&#39;s no longer a form of government that claims to champion the cause of the marginalized while craftily concealing the domination of the under-privileged by autocrats and oligarchs---it&#39;s the real the thing: true government by popular representation.
And it&#39;s clear that people view Obama as a human being--- someone with a conscience, who believes that America stands for democracy, liberty, freedom, and the rule of law.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Tories At The Table, More Water In The Liberal Hull</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/more-tories-at-the-table-more-water-in-the-liberal-hull/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/more-tories-at-the-table-more-water-in-the-liberal-hull/</guid>
      <description>Was it Warren Buffet who reminded us of the irrationality in the stock market? What was it he said, stock markets are people driven and people are irrational? I&#39;d like to add the movements of populist governments to his irrational people bit as, it seems to me, both populist governments and stock markets are guided by public opinion. If public opinion is an expression of human behavior, (run that one by your local shrink if you like,) does that make it the result of feelings, instincts, and herd-like responses to media induced perceptions (not a herd of hippo&#39;s mind you, that&#39;s the U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stimulating Interest</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/stimulating-interest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/stimulating-interest/</guid>
      <description>So world leaders (note: 20 of them) have agreed to come together in a first ever meeting of the G20 to discuss a restructuring of global financial market systems. Finally, economic and politically minded people everywhere are revisiting the decisions that have shaped our global economy into the fertile soil for crisis that it has become.
Milton Friedman&#39;s legacy is under attack. The concepts of nationalism and socialism in the state are not only being reconsidered, they are being re-instituted as we speak (the nationalization of big banks globally).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wallstreet&#39;s Liquidity Problem</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2008 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/wall-streets-liquidity-problem/</guid>
      <description>It doesn&#39;t take a rocket scientist to see that addressing the liquidity problem on Wall Street by borrowing to restore the ability to lend does not address the underlying aggregate debt issue.
The common sense approach says that to avoid a sudden crash or some kind of long drawn out debt deflation, the American Government needs to address the ability of the real economy to earn, borrow and spend. And in this sense yes, much of the relief could have gone to debtors at large and not the creditors, who to pay their new debts will have to lend more.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>