<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>house on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/house/</link>
    <description>Recent content in house on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/house/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Tokyo Megaplex </title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-07-26-music-playlist-tokyo-megaplex/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/current/2020-07-26-music-playlist-tokyo-megaplex/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Tokyo Megaplex - Pinapple House Party, The Hole Foods Experience, Ahhhhh, The Price Is Wrong  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Tokyo MegaplexAs I understand, Tokyo Megaplex is a Brooklyn musical artist. I listened to a few of their tracks and enjoyed these ones.If you can listen beyond the Hip Hop (a decidedly specific segment of the musical spectrum), they could go nicely with augmented reality. Augmented Reality is a concept developed in recent years by designer KEIICHIMATSUDA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist: Exercise Bike</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-01-hello-music-playlist-exercise-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-01-hello-music-playlist-exercise-bike/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Juanitos: Sai-k-delic Party, Mark Grant: Jazzy Kinda Sum&amp;#39;n, Dr. Kucho! &amp;amp; Gregor Salto: Can&amp;#39;t Stop Playing (Oliver Heldens &amp;amp; Gregor Salto Remix), FISHER: Losing It, Dom Dolla: Take It (Sonny Fodera Remix), David Bendeth: Feel The Real (Jazz &amp;#39;n&amp;#39; Groove Ultra Classic Mix), Big Sexy: Another World (Passport Remix), Paul Johnson: Get Get Down, Armand Van Helden: You Don&amp;#39;t Know Me, Claptone: Cream, Bow Wow Wow: I Want Candy, Todd Terje: Inspector Norse, Ida Corr vs Fedde Le Grand: Let Me Think About It, Alex Gaudino, Featuring Shena: Watch Out, Crystal Waters: 100% Pure Love, Johnny Corporate: Sunday Shoutin&amp;#39; [Original Mix], Trueby Trio: Make A Move (Spiller Remix), Noze: Remember Love, You Man &amp;amp; Jerge: Everybody, Koop: Relaxin at Club F****n (Dorfmeister vs.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>