<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Psychology on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/psychology/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Psychology on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/psychology/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Principles</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/principles/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/principles/</guid>
      <description>It is honorable to respect all peoples, given they are not acting outside the social contract, nor seeking to usurp unjustly another&#39;s rights or freedoms.
The law protects people in societies and enables societies to function. To the extent it remains to do so, it should be upheld at every turn. When there are laws that do not serve all citizens in a society equally, those laws should be challenged and amended.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizational Psychology</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/organizational-psychology/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/organizational-psychology/</guid>
      <description>Numerous studies have examined what intangible and tangible factors might cause one organization to outperform others over a period of time. There is no question that ideas and talent are invaluable, but it is no longer any surprise that the single most important factor affecting organizational performance is organizational psychology. Here are a few examples:
Ray Dalio runs Bridgewater Associates, one of the largest hedge funds in the world. In Connecticut, he&#39;s got 1500 people, some of whom are the best and brightest brains in the financial sector, but does Ray cite his PhDs, research acumen, and process as his number one a comparative advantage?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Characteristics Of A Winner</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/characteristics-of-a-winner/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/characteristics-of-a-winner/</guid>
      <description>Innovative Hard working Believes in what he/she is doing Focuses on details Maintains a calm and relaxed presence Well spoken (concise&amp;hellip;excellent word choice) In-it-to-win-it Responsible Intelligent Continually developing Keeps moving to the front Gets as much perspective as possible Accepts where he/she is at Lets go of errors Genuine Thorough Dutiful Light-hearted, fun Prepared Attentive Implements systems for thoughts and actions Takes action as often as possible Creative Prioritizes actions to optimal Makes time for relationships Presents value and credentials when criticized Expects attacks from others but does not hold this against them Doesn&amp;rsquo;t take life personally Courteous Engages with different social groups without owning differences Maintains a well tuned psychology Limits unprepared actions Integrates self-checking processes Keeps a narrow focus to maintain effectiveness Doesn&amp;rsquo;t flinch at criticism (nor own it) Doesn&amp;rsquo;t spin, stretch the truth or lie Doesn&amp;rsquo;t sink to a lower level Accepts the behaviour of others with humour keen Discusses what successful actions he/she is doing</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Progress: Getting Along In Life</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/getting-along-in-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Dec 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/getting-along-in-life/</guid>
      <description>Inspiration is about being on the upswing. Find out what gets you there, find out what keeps you there, and make a habit of it. Success is about a good nights sleep, either tomorrow is Sunday or you are prepared to meet it. Self-improvement is a lifestyle. Expectations are so yesterday. Grey area is dangerous. Make sure you spell it out. Prodigality is tiresome. Habits are the measuring stick you are looking for.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>