<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>rock on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/rock/</link>
    <description>Recent content in rock on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/rock/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Lithuanian Music, Indie Rock</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-08-01-music-playlist-lithuanian-indie-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-08-01-music-playlist-lithuanian-indie-music/</guid>
      <description>Songs:No Real Pioneers - at Ymir Audio, Verslo rizikos rezervas - Mano vaikas prazilo, Verslo Rizikos Rezervas - Kur plauki?, Biplan - Labas rytas, Daddy Was A Milkman - Seasons, Empti Radio laga, Donny Montell feat. Mark Les - LEISK MYLET, FREAKS ON FLOOR: Star,Rasabasa: Interstellar, KaYra: Alligator  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Lithuanian Music</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Indie Rock, Featuring Spoon</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-07-30-music-playlist-indie-rock-spoon/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2020-07-30-music-playlist-indie-rock-spoon/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Spoon - Finer Feelings, Foster The People - Pick U Up, Datarock- Fa Fa Fa, The Zolas - Molotov Girls, the ponys - double vision, Vampire Weekend - A-Punk, Modest Mouse - Dashboard, Vampire Weekend - Cousins , Arcade Fire - No Cars Go, Belle and Sebastian - Legal Man, Vampire Weekend: A Punk, Electric Light Orchestra: Mr. Blue Sky, Pheonix: 1901
 Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Indie Rock</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Music You Can Work To</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-02-hello-music-playlist-work/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-02-hello-music-playlist-work/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Audionautix: Fat Caps, Roboskater, Opus One, Cycles, Yeah Yeah, Ice Cold, Ooh Hey, Sunday Spirit, Radio Rock, Macaroon 5, Pop Star, Get A Move On, Sk8tboard, Tech Talk, Vanishing Horizon, Lightning Bugs, Code Blue, Rubix Cube, Carlo Virz: Tommaso Groove, John Deley: Bumber Tag, Silent Partner: Weekend In The City, Spaz Cardigan: Rinse and Repeat,  Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Free Beats, Loops, and CutsNotesThere&#39;s a lot of good music made for television streams these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist: Exercise Bike</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-01-hello-music-playlist-exercise-bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-12-01-hello-music-playlist-exercise-bike/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Juanitos: Sai-k-delic Party, Mark Grant: Jazzy Kinda Sum&amp;#39;n, Dr. Kucho! &amp;amp; Gregor Salto: Can&amp;#39;t Stop Playing (Oliver Heldens &amp;amp; Gregor Salto Remix), FISHER: Losing It, Dom Dolla: Take It (Sonny Fodera Remix), David Bendeth: Feel The Real (Jazz &amp;#39;n&amp;#39; Groove Ultra Classic Mix), Big Sexy: Another World (Passport Remix), Paul Johnson: Get Get Down, Armand Van Helden: You Don&amp;#39;t Know Me, Claptone: Cream, Bow Wow Wow: I Want Candy, Todd Terje: Inspector Norse, Ida Corr vs Fedde Le Grand: Let Me Think About It, Alex Gaudino, Featuring Shena: Watch Out, Crystal Waters: 100% Pure Love, Johnny Corporate: Sunday Shoutin&amp;#39; [Original Mix], Trueby Trio: Make A Move (Spiller Remix), Noze: Remember Love, You Man &amp;amp; Jerge: Everybody, Koop: Relaxin at Club F****n (Dorfmeister vs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music Playlist - Saki Kaskas</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-11-01-hello-music-playlist-saki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/motivation/2019-11-01-hello-music-playlist-saki/</guid>
      <description>Songs:Saki Kaskamanidis: Little Sweaty Sow, Changes, Fast Lane, Prime Funk (Extended), Feta Cheese, Globular Cluster, Siwash Rock, Knossos (Remix), Saturnight, Callista, Bulbular Swirl, Fasolatha, Nashat, Powerslide, Amorphous Being, Showcase, Toxic Exhaust, Flimsy, Gore, Bleary
 Playlist Title:&amp;nbsp;Saki KaskamanidisNotesSaki was straight-up a monster talent, and humble, and authentic. Listen to his music if you want to amp up your workout, get technical, or kick-it, back in the crib.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>