<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Trade on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/trade/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Trade on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/tags/trade/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Smaller Trade Deals, More Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/smaller-trade-deals-more-trade/</guid>
      <description>Rarely have free trade debaters--on all sides--had better opportunities to wag tongues. The long-standing era of free trade deals that in Canada started with the Canada-US Free Trade Agreement in 1987 (CUSFTA), superseded by the North American Free Trade Agreement (NAFTA) in 1994, has run squarely into a pronounced US protectionist revival that glaringly threatens the now deeply integrated global trade regime. This is not, by the way, an uncontested protectionist movement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Statistics And Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>National and international level statistics that report macroeconomic indicators, like nominal and real inflation, international transaction flows, and trade statistics, are relied on by market participants, policy makers and stakeholders as inputs to critical decisions. More often than not, macroeconomic statistics are taken as reliable, after-all, those are our official statistics, right?. But just how reliable are they? Unfortunately, the answer is that aligning statistics with underlying realities is a challenging task, and mainstream macroeconomic statistics should, even in the best of cases, be taken with a grain of salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is Macroeconomics</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-are-macroeconomics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-are-macroeconomics/</guid>
      <description>What is macroeconomics Macroeconomics is the field of economics that deals with aggregated quantities. Microeconomics, for example, might deal with firm level economics, while macroeconomics might deal with aggregate firms level economics, the economics of all the firms in an economy together. Macroeconomics therefore includes the study of national level and supranational level economics.
What kind of indicators are macroeconomic? Macroeconomic indicators include trade indicators, like the trade balance, and trade openness, but also indicators that describe other facets of the economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Is International Trade</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-international-trade/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/what-is-international-trade/</guid>
      <description>What is international trade? International trade is the movement of goods across national borders. Because bilateral exchange rates change frequently, international trade is watched closely by national and supranational governments. Small changes in currency pair spreads can impact the movement of goods across borders and, as a consequence, the health of a nation&#39;s domestic industry and its employment levels.
How do organizations measure international trade? Physical goods (commodity trade) are tracked by governments when they enter various economic and trade zones within an economy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Liberalization And Sector Productivity</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper analyzes the effects of trade liberalization on productivity at the sector level. This is done with a multivariable regression of relative gross labour productivity on sector trade, between the U.S. and Canada, relative to total trade, between Canada and the world. A set of before and after treatment variables are used to distinguish the difference between the effect of trade openness before the NAFTA preferential trade agreement and after the agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case for Continued Pursuit of Emu Accession in Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper reviews a variety of academic publications, including those from authors who produced gravity models, and presents trade arguments for and against Lithuanian accession to the European Monetary Union (EMU). While the results prompt the author to argue in favour of accession, there is no commentary on either the benefits of reduced default risk or the costs of potential negative externalities like declines in living conditions or increased brain drain and population exodus that could result if accession causes tax increases, higher unemployment or lowered government expenditure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case For Continued Pursuit Of the Euro</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-the-euro-in-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Nov 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-the-euro-in-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>Download Trade Openness And Sector Productivity</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>