<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Liberalization And Sector Productivity</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper analyzes the effects of trade liberalization on productivity at the sector level. This is done with a multivariable regression of relative gross labour productivity on sector trade, between the U.S. and Canada, relative to total trade, between Canada and the world. A set of before and after treatment variables are used to distinguish the difference between the effect of trade openness before the NAFTA preferential trade agreement and after the agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case for Continued Pursuit of Emu Accession in Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper reviews a variety of academic publications, including those from authors who produced gravity models, and presents trade arguments for and against Lithuanian accession to the European Monetary Union (EMU). While the results prompt the author to argue in favour of accession, there is no commentary on either the benefits of reduced default risk or the costs of potential negative externalities like declines in living conditions or increased brain drain and population exodus that could result if accession causes tax increases, higher unemployment or lowered government expenditure.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>