<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Statistics on Cloud Nine</title>
    <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/statistics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Statistics on Cloud Nine</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <copyright>Copyright</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://cloudnine.github.io/categories/statistics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Statistics And Blockchain</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-23-trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-02-23-trade-statistics-and-blockchain/</guid>
      <description>National and international level statistics that report macroeconomic indicators, like nominal and real inflation, international transaction flows, and trade statistics, are relied on by market participants, policy makers and stakeholders as inputs to critical decisions. More often than not, macroeconomic statistics are taken as reliable, after-all, those are our official statistics, right?. But just how reliable are they? Unfortunately, the answer is that aligning statistics with underlying realities is a challenging task, and mainstream macroeconomic statistics should, even in the best of cases, be taken with a grain of salt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What Are Statistics</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-11-what-are-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2016-01-11-what-are-statistics/</guid>
      <description>What are statistics? Statistics are transformations of data through calculation. While in theory any calculation done with data yields a statistic, in practice statistics are associated with scientific and field specific calculations. For example, during preparation phase your data is frequently explored and analysed using simple plotting techniques that present meaningful descriptive statistics from the data or data subset, like the mean, median, and/or quartile ranges. As another example, in macroeconomics, various calculations with data yield well known statistics like GDP, inflation, or trade balance by sector.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trade Liberalization And Sector Productivity</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-12-05-trade-liberalization-and-sector-productivity/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper analyzes the effects of trade liberalization on productivity at the sector level. This is done with a multivariable regression of relative gross labour productivity on sector trade, between the U.S. and Canada, relative to total trade, between Canada and the world. A set of before and after treatment variables are used to distinguish the difference between the effect of trade openness before the NAFTA preferential trade agreement and after the agreement.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Case for Continued Pursuit of Emu Accession in Lithuania</title>
      <link>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://cloudnine.github.io/archives/2011-03-15-a-case-for-continued-pursuit-of-emu-accession-in-lithuania/</guid>
      <description>Abstract This paper reviews arguments in academic literature for and against Lithuania&#39;s pursuit of EMU accession. The results indicate Lithuania stands to gain in trade with ROW and with the EMU on completion of change-over to the Euro. Moreover, trade specialization and the potential of under-trading, promise further gains from Euro accession. Economies of scale ensure that gains from trade and currency management cost reductions will be large relative to GDP.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>